(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-01T04:11:30.320399",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
のじゃあ〜
Noja~~
あらあら、メラメラ、あちち、めらあ〜！
My my, blazing, hot, blazing!
ほろらいぶ遊びまわりたい、火消しアサラマンダのアちちメラナのじゃあ〜！
I want to roam around Hololive, I'm Asalamanda the firefighter, hot Merana-no-ja!
のじゃ！
Noja!
こんばんは。
Good evening.
のじゃこんばんは。
Good evening, noja.
のじゃんばんは、後ろのじゃんばんは。
Noja evening, the noja evening behind me.
あ、アンケートで高評価をお願いするのを忘れたのじゃ、今入れるのじゃ。
Ah, I forgot to ask for ratings in the poll, I'll add it now, noja.
高評価を押してほしいのじゃ、よいしょ。
I want you to press high rating, heave-ho.
したのじゃ。
Done, noja.
いいのじゃ、よいしょ。
That's good, heave-ho.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
遅れた？
Late?
遅れたのじゃ。
I'm late, noja.
よし。
Alright.
こんばんはなのじゃ。
Good evening, noja.
のじゃんばんはあ！
Noja evening!
今日は、今日はもともと元の予定じゃと
Today, originally, according to the original schedule...
リズム天国で遊ばせていただく予定だったんじゃが
...I was scheduled to play Rhythm Heaven, but
キャプボ、キャプチャーボードっていうスイッチつの画面を配信に映す機械が
the capture board, the machine that projects the Nintendo Switch screen onto the stream,
なんか不調で、不調で映らなくて
for some reason malfunctioned and wouldn't display,
いろんな人に聞いたので聞いたのですが
so I asked various people, and although I asked,
うん、いろんな人がいろんな対処法を教えてくれたんじゃが、なんか1時間ぐらいやっても難しくて
yeah, various people taught me various ways to fix it, but even after trying for an hour it was too difficult,
ゲームを変更しましたのじゃ。
so I changed the game, noja.
さっき最初からそうずっ て言ってた。
You've been saying that from the start.
確かに！忘れてたのじゃ！
That's true! I forgot, noja!
忘れてたのじゃ、本当にごめんなのじゃ、忘れてたのじゃ、さっき言ったことを忘れてたのじゃ。
I forgot, I'm really sorry, noja, I forgot, I forgot what I said earlier.
なので、リズム天国は、リズム天国はまたの
So, Rhythm Heaven, Rhythm Heaven will be...
なんか、詳しい人に相談をさせていただいて直すので、直したら遊びたいと思っておりますのじゃ。
Consulting someone knowledgeable and fixing it, so once it's fixed, I hope to play it, noja.
なので、今日はジオゲッサーで遊ぶのじゃー！
So today we're playing GeoGuessr, noja!
ジオゲッサー
GeoGuessr...
お前ら知ってる？
Do you guys know it?
お前らはジオゲッサーというゲームを知っているんだ。
You guys know a game called GeoGuessr.
ジオゲッサーをご存知かの
Do you know GeoGuessr...?
わしが唯一遊ぶゲーム、
The only game I play,
唯一遊ぶゲームなのじゃ。
the only game I play.
でもデビューの準備でバタバタしてて最近全然遊んでなかったから、
But I've been busy preparing for my debut and haven't played at all recently,
最近全然遊んでなかったからすごい久しぶりに遊ぶのじゃ。
so I'll be playing it for the first time in a long time.
ジオゲッサーはどういうゲームかというと、
As for what kind of game GeoGuessr is,
なんか日本、どこでもいいんじゃが、世界のある場所、世界のある場所に落とされるのじゃ。
it drops you somewhere in Japan—anywhere, really—somewhere in the world.
で、360度見わたすのじゃ。
And you look around 360 degrees.
ここがどこか当てるゲームなのじゃ。
It's a game where you guess where you are.
好きなのじゃ、すごい好きなのじゃ。
I love it, I love it so much.
そう、AZKi先輩がめちゃくちゃ遊んでいらっしゃるゲーム。
Yeah, it's a game AZKi-senpai plays a ton.
AZKi先輩ともね、いつか絶対遊んでみたい、遊んでほしいなって思ってるのじゃ。
I'd definitely love to play with AZKi-senpai sometime.
今日は日本マップ、ジャパンマップで遊ぼうと思っておるのじゃ。
Today, I'm thinking of playing on the Japan map.
日本のどこかに落とされて、
You get dropped somewhere in Japan,
で、今日本どこにいるかなってのを当てる、当てようと思うのじゃ。
and you try to guess where in Japan you are.
動かさず見渡さず自分の位置を見極める、それはノー移動、ノーマム、ノーパンというあの、基地外モードなのじゃ。
Figuring out your position without moving or looking around... That's the crazy mode called No Move, No Zoom, No Pan.
ノー移動のパンの、あの、もう何もわかんないのじゃ。
The No Move, Pan, No Zoom... you have no idea what's going on.
運ゲーなのじゃ、あれ。
It's a game of luck, that.
そう、今日さ、今日さ、
Yeah, today... today...
昨日もさ、昨日の配信見てくれてたおならさ、わかると思うんじゃが、
If you watched yesterday's stream, you probably know, but...
あの、なんだっけ？
Um, what was it?
あの、カクカクしてたじゃろ？ わしがカクカクしてたじゃろ？
Um, it was stuttering, right? I was stuttering, right?
前、前話とかにするのじゃ。
Let's make it a 'pre-story' or something.
なんか機材トラブルがめちゃくちゃ多くてご迷惑をおかけしておりますのじゃ。
I've been having a lot of equipment trouble lately and causing a lot of trouble.
頑張って、頑張って、慣れるのじゃ。
I'll do my best to get used to it.
わしも早くベテランVTuberになってあんまり機材トラブルが起きないようにしたいと思いますのじゃ。今日は頑張りますのじゃ。
I hope to become a veteran VTuber soon so I don't have equipment trouble. I'll do my best today.
じゃあ移動します。よっしゃー！
Well then, let's move. Let's go!
聞こえてるのじゃ？
Can you hear me?
どうかな？こ、これぐらい？これぐらいか。よし！
How's this? About this much? This much? Okay!
できた！できたと思うのじゃ。
Done! I think it's done.
じゃあ、遊んでいくのじゃ。何で、何で遊ぶのがいいかの、何で遊ぶのがいいかの、
Now, let's play. What mode should we play on...?
なんかいろんなモードがあって、あの、さっき言ったノー移動のパン、ノービュームとか、ノービュームとか、ビュームとかいろんなモードがあるんじゃが、
There are various modes... like I said earlier, No Move, Pan, No Zoom, Zoom, and various other modes.
であと時間、時間とかも、あの、決められるのじゃ。
And you can also set the time limit.
好きな時間でできるんじゃが、好きな時間でできるんじゃが、
You can do it for whatever time you like...
何分、まずはふつうに。ふつうってどれぐらいかの？
How many minutes? First, Normal. What's Normal like?
ふつうってやっぱタイムリミットなし？
Does Normal have no time limit?
5分とか？どれぐらい？時間設定どれぐらいがいいのかの？
5 minutes? How much? What's a good time setting?
5分。まずふつうに5分ぐらい。ムーブで5分ぐらい。了解なのじゃ。
5 minutes? First, about 5 minutes on Normal. About 5 minutes with Move. Got it.
ムーブあんまりやったことないのじゃ、酔っちゃうから。
I haven't played Move much, it makes me motion sick.
やってみるのじゃ。
Let's try it.
基本設定、基本設定ムーブの5分で。
Basic settings: Move with 5 minutes.
そう、制限ないとね、ジオゲッサーって制限ないとね、山、山奥とかに落とされるとね、もう本当に、本当に1時間とかかかっちゃう
Yeah, if there's no limit... GeoGuessr, if there's no limit, and you get dropped deep in the mountains, it seriously takes like an hour.
しょうこともあるから
Sometimes it happens, so...
じゃあ早速やってみますのじゃあ日本マップ！
Let's try it right away then, the Japan map!
あれBGMが乗ってる
Huh, the BGM is playing.
BGM聞こえとる？BGMうるさいかの？どうじゃ？
Can you hear the BGM? Is it too loud? What do you think?
おいしょ
Heave-ho.
BGMどう？あきる…あきるのし？あきるのしなんか聞いたことあるのじゃ
How's the BGM? Akiru... Akiruno City? I feel like I've heard of Akiruno City.
なんか ちょっと待って、ちっちゃい
Wait a second, it's small.
なんかこのへんだった気がするのじゃ、千葉とかなんかこ
I feel like it was around here, like Chiba or somewhere...
えっと これが 多分
Um, this is probably...
東京電力 うるさくない？ちょうどいい？
Tokyo Electric Power? Is it not loud? Just right?
大きい？
Too big?
ちょっと大きい？ちょっと大きい？BGM 2つ
A bit too big? A bit too big? Two BGMs?
はっ 切れった？BGM切れた？
Ah, did it cut out? Did the BGM cut out?
どうじゃ？どうじゃ？
How is it? How is it?
なんか東京電力なのは分かったから 電話番号とか見るのじゃ、042
Well, I figured out it's Tokyo Electric Power, so I'll check the phone number... 042.
042、042…えっと 042どのへんだったかな？
042, 042... Um, around where was 042?
すごい山だね、すごい山の中なのじゃ
That's an incredible mountain, right in the middle of the mountains.
BGM下げてほしい、了解なのじゃ
You want me to lower the BGM? Understood.
どう？下がってる？
How's that? Is it lower?
BGM下がってる？いい感じ？
Is the BGM lower? Feeling good?
どうじゃ？おんではいい感じ
How is it? This time it feels good.
なんかその…市とかはまだ全然分かんなくて、いっしょ
Like, as for the city and stuff, I still have no idea at all...
都道府県は分かるのじゃ。都道府県は分かって、市は知ってるのと知ら…
I know the prefecture. I know the prefecture, but the city... do I know it or...
知らん。ほぼ知らない？配信BGMの方がいい？
I don't. I pretty much don't know? Is stream BGM better?
じゃあじゃあ
Well then...
どう？どう？
How is it? How is it?
これでいい？BGMほしい？
Is this good? Do you want BGM?
あと3分しかない、確かに。ちょっちょっちょっちょっちょ、川、川が、川があるのじゃ
We only have 3 minutes left, that's true. Wait wait wait... river, there's a river.
でも結構読みづらいな、読みづらいな。き、きぬ…きわだ、きわだだい、きわだ
But it's pretty hard to read, hard to read. Ki, kinu... Kiwada, Kiwadadai, Kiwada...
あきるのし、でも結構山の中だから、うん、山の中だから
Akiruno City, but it's pretty deep in the mountains, yeah, because it's in the mountains.
なんかあきるのしの中でも結構奥々言っちゃっていい気がしていって、きわだ、なんて書いてあるんだろう
I feel like it's pretty deep inside Akiruno City. Kiwada... I wonder what it says.
ほかにあのへんに書いてないかな。おいしょ
Let me check if there's anything else written around there. Heave-ho.
よいしょよいしょ。有料道路…川も大きくないのじゃ
Heave-ho. Toll road... The river isn't that big either.
川も大きくないのじゃ。よいしょ。よいしょ
The river isn't that big either. Heave-ho. Heave-ho.
ちょっと今。よいしょよいしょ。ど、ど、ドアセリドキンチョウ、川の前
Just now. Heave-ho. Do... do... Doaseri Dokincho, in front of the river.
ドアセリドキンチョウしてるで、川の名前がどっかにあるかの
I'm getting nervous, I wonder if the river's name is somewhere.
めっちゃ山の中なのだ。でもめっちゃヒシザワっていう文字を見る。西多摩
It's super deep in the mountains. But I keep seeing the word "Hishizawa". Nishitama.
西多摩、うーん こっち方面かな、じゃあ
Nishitama, hmm, I guess it's this direction.
西多摩であきるのし こっち側かな
Nishitama, Akiruno City, is it this side?
え、ドキンチョウしてる
Huh, I'm getting nervous.
なんかこのへんのどっかのお町とかでもおかしくなさそうじゃが、でも結構山の中な気がするんだよね
It wouldn't seem strange for it to be in some town around here, but I feel like it's pretty deep in the mountains.
進むのじゃ
Let's move on.
わしが住んでた山とは違うのじゃ
This is different from the mountains I used to live in.
民宿 大岳渓流 042
Minshuku Otake Keiryu, 042...
もっと奥多摩あたり。確かに
More around Okutama. True.
なんか書いてある。大岳清流 釣道楽
Something's written. Otake Seiryu, Tsuri Douraku.
こういう名前の山がありそう。大岳渓流。このへんにありそうな気がするのじゃ
Sounds like a mountain with a name like that. Otake Keiryu. I feel like it's around here.
ないのじゃ。初見でど山に落とされたのじゃ。わしが山住んでるからかな
It's not. I got dropped right into the deep mountains on my first try. Is it because I live in the mountains?
一旦このへんに、あ、あった。大岳山
Once around here... Ah, there it is. Mt. Otake.
ほら、の、どっか。このへんのどっか。
Look, um, somewhere. Somewhere around here.
もっとこっちだったのかしょ。
Must've been more over this way, huh.
なんて読むのじゃ? ヨー、シャワーフィッシュ、グランド？
How do you read this? Yo... Shower Fish Ground?
むずかしいのじゃあ！
That's so hard!
山暮らしへの配慮。釣りは釣りボリですかし たことないのじゃ。
Consideration for mountain living. Fishing is at a fishing pond? I've never done that.
ちょっと山の中難しかったの。でもこの多分これ何て読むじゃ大学さん?
The mountains were a bit hard. But this, what do you read this? Daigaku-san?
この山があってその近く。あと西たまってるのが見えたからこっちの方なのとおきるの七かくぐらい？
There's this mountain nearby. And I saw something pooling to the west, so around 7 minutes or so from this direction?
むずいのかじゃ。次いくのじゃ、山じゃないとこに落としてほしいのじゃ。
It's so hard. Next one, I want you to drop me somewhere that's not a mountain.
山じゃないところに落としてくれたら嬉しいのじゃ。
I'd be happy if you dropped me somewhere without mountains.
関西電力だからこのへんのどっかなのじゃ。
It's Kansai Electric Power, so it's somewhere around here.
えっと、とした時に山が南にない。南に山がないのじゃ。
Um, when I placed it, there are no mountains to the south. There are no mountains to the south.
で、北の方にはちょっぴり。よよ進んでみるのじゃ。
And to the north, just a tiny bit. Let's try going forward.
何軒かの…稲尾。稲尾。
A few houses... Inao. Inao.
めっちゃ田んぼなのじゃ。でもね、田んぼってね、日本のどこにでもありますからね。日本のどこにでも田んぼってありますからね。
It's super full of rice fields. But you know, rice fields are everywhere in Japan. Rice fields exist everywhere in Japan.
むうばり、むずいのかじゃ。
Mubari... It's so hard.
この辺に書いてある。あーー、兵庫なのじゃ。
It's written around here. Ah, it's Hyogo.
加東市。の
Kato City. Of...
確かにこのへん、このへんめっちゃ溜息多いのじゃ。加東市。
Indeed, around here, there are so many irrigation ponds. Kato City.
川の東のとこ。稲尾。加東市稲尾。田んぼめっちゃあるからかな。うわ、稲尾を探すのむずいそ。
East of the river. Inao. Inao, Kato City. Probably because there are so many rice fields. Man, finding Inao is hard.
もうちょいヒント欲しいな。もうちょい広く撮りたいけど。
I want a bit more hint. I want a slightly wider view though.
むずいかな。地区が、稲尾地区。
Is it hard? The district is Inao District.
でもこういうしかないのか。稲尾を稲尾を探していくのじゃ。これ探していくの苦手苦手じゃから。
Is this the only way? I'll search for Inao. Because searching for things like this is really not my strong suit.
山とか見たいけど、NNW見たいけど。ちょっと多いのじゃここへんは。
I want to see mountains or something, like NNW. There are quite a few around here.
建物がある。あとはなんかヒントあるかな? あんまないのじゃ。
There are buildings. Are there any other hints? Not really.
溜池多い。稲尾。溜池も多いし、田んぼも多い。田んぼも多いのじゃ。
Lots of irrigation ponds. Inao. Lots of irrigation ponds, and lots of rice fields. There are lots of rice fields.
稲尾。稲尾どこ? 稲尾ででてきてほしいのじゃ！稲尾ーー！
Inao. Where is Inao? I want Inao to pop up! Inao--!
ちょ、もうちょいヒント欲しいか? もうちょいヒント触りたいか? もうちょいヒント探したいか?
Wait, do you want a bit more hint? Do you want to touch/find more hints? Want to search for more hints?
ちょっと進みたいとは思おうんじゃが。なんかねあんまり情報がなさそうじゃからね、その道路番号とかは。あーー、ミスったほう進んじゃった。
Though I think I want to advance a bit. It seems like there isn't much info, like road numbers and stuff. Ah-- I went the wrong way.
なさそうじゃから、いえ。うーーん。稲尾。ね、山がある。
Since it seems unlikely, no. Hmm. Inao. See, there are mountains.
加東市。ほ、保険エース。なんかそういう情報しかないな。
Kato City. Insurance Ace. There's only info like that.
稲尾。稲尾。稲尾。もっと情報が、稲尾分団。
Inao. Inao. Inao. More info, Inao Fire Brigade.
なんか稲尾以外の稲尾っぽい文字情報がいただけるとうわ、稲尾って立ってるってことは何かとの間な気がする。
If I could get character info resembling Inao other than Inao... Wait, the fact that Inao is standing makes me feel like it's between something.
何かと何かの狭間な気がするのじゃ。こういうね。こういうなんかてんてんてんの狭間もしているのじゃ。稲尾、稲尾。ないの。
Feels like it's in the gap between something and something. Like this. It's also making a gap with dots like this. Inao, Inao. None.
5分あると無限じゃの。5分ってめっちゃ長い。
Having 5 minutes is endless. 5 minutes is super long.
5分あったら大沼。大沼できるのじゃ。大沼できますのじゃ。
If there's 5 minutes, Oonuma. We can do Oonuma. We can do Oonuma.
家がない。でも家少なめなきもするんじゃがな。地区、地区、地区。
No houses. Though I feel like there are fewer houses. District, district, district.
地区
District
山
Mountain
こっち側の山もしかで見えないから、こっち側な気はするんじゃが、
I can't really see the mountains on this side, so I feel like it's this side...
稲生？
Inao?
ないのじゃ！
It's not here!
5分長くない？
Isn't 5 minutes too long?
5分長いのじゃ！
It's way too long!
ない。
None.
探す、探すのじゃー！
Search, gotta search!
こういう時って歩き回った方がいいのか？
In times like this, is it better to walk around?
歩き回った方がいいのか？
Is it better to walk around?
それとも、なんじゃ、
Or, you know,
こっちで探しまくった方がいいのか？どっちなんだろ？
should I search like crazy over here? Which one is it?
普段は1分のノー(move)でしかやらないのじゃ。
Normally, I only do 1-minute no-move rounds.
だからその、細かいとこまであんまりいか、最後まであんまりいかないのじゃ。
So I don't go into details, nor do I go all the way to the end.
え、近くて笑った。
Eh, I laughed because it was so close.
本当だ！ね、稲生あったのじゃ！
Really! Hey, Inao was there!
稲生あったのじゃ！
Inao was there!
なんか置いたとこに稲生あったのじゃ。
Inao was right where I placed it.
確かに。え、意外と道路ある。
True. Eh, there are surprisingly roads.
意外と道路ある。ここまで歩いたら道路番号が見れそう。
Surprisingly many roads. If I walk up here, I might see the road number.
おしゃべりもしたいから。
I also want to chat.
なるほどなのだ。稲生ここにありましたのだ。
I see. Inao was right here.
画面に映ってたかもしれないじゃ。
It might have been on screen.
画面に映ってたのに、見落とし、見逃しそうになっていた可能性あり。
Even though it was on screen, I might have almost missed it.
次行くのじゃ。わしも賢くゲストしたいのじゃ。
Moving on. I want to guess smartly too.
わしも賢く、ね、かっこよくね。
Smartly, you know, coolly.
え、山見えるSW。北海道な気がするのじゃ。
Eh, mountains visible to the SW. I feel like it's Hokkaido.
北海道でちょっと見やすい電柱を見たいんじゃが、北海道ではあるんじゃが。
I want to see easily identifiable utility poles in Hokkaido, though it is Hokkaido.
いや、無言なら高速ってわけでもないのじゃ。
No, it's not like silence means it's a highway.
あの、あんまりその、最後まで新光一丁目18。
Um, not really going all the way to... Shinko 1-chome 18.
ちょ、北海道のどこかが知りたいんじゃが。電柱がちゃんと見える場所がポジショニングが取れないのじゃ。見えないの。
Um, I want to know where in Hokkaido. But I can't position myself to see the poles clearly. I can't see them.
ちょっと移動するのじゃ。北海道では若くてで、えっと。
I'll move a bit. In Hokkaido, young and, um.
なんじゃが。
What is it.
あ、わしが被ってる。ちょっと小さくなるのじゃ。
Ah, I'm covering it. I'll get a bit smaller.
豊浦町病院？
Toyoura Town Hospital?
あ、なんか書いてある。しが書いてある。見るのじゃ。しじゃなかったのじゃ。残念。
Ah, something is written. 'Shi' is written. Let's see. It wasn't 'shi'. Too bad.
しだと思ったんじゃがの。なんで分かったかというと、電柱が北海道の電柱じゃし。
I thought it was 'shi', though. Why did I know? Because it's a Hokkaido utility pole.
さっき言った最初の地点に41番だから、やっぱ札幌の近くとなのじゃ。ここの番号で分かるのじゃ。
...at the first point mentioned earlier it's number 41, so it's close to Sapporo. You can tell from the number here.
そっから、でも結構山が見えたから。
From there, though, quite a few mountains were visible.
最初のとこ戻るのじゃ。
Going back to the start.
山がね、結構ね、SWこっちに、多分この山な気がする、こっちの方な気がする。違うかな。
Mountains are, quite, SW, this way, probably I feel like it's this mountain. Is it wrong?
この山脈な気がす、でっかい山。
I feel like it's this mountain range, a huge mountain.
山が見えたからSW。
Since mountains were visible, SW.
市街地からは外れてる、外れてるからぼうじゃろうな、これ。
It's away from the urban area, away from it, so it's probably bou, right?
どうなんだろ。電柱は全国共通じゃないのじゃ。
How is it? Utility poles are not common nationwide.
あと北海道にしかこの手厚いスペースみたいなのないのじゃ。
And only Hokkaido has these generous spacing-like things.
あとは、こっからどうしようかな。なんかもうちょい細かい情報が載ってるところがあるといいんじゃが。
Also, what should I do from here? It would be nice if there was a place with more detailed info.
何？これ。ゴミ捨て場とか見るか。ゴミ捨て場見るか。北海道住宅。
What? This. Should I check the garbage dump? Check the garbage dump. Hokkaido housing.
浅美津団地。浅美津団地。
Asamitsu Danchi. Asamitsu Danchi.
あとこのトヨタンクも寒いとこにしかないのじゃ。
Also this Toyo tank is only in cold places.
結構な、結構な山。
Quite a, quite a mountain.
北海道こういう旗めっちゃ多いのじゃ。朝里川温泉。
Hokkaido has so many flags like this. Asarigawa Onsen.
あさ公園
Asa Park
小樽
Otaru
市がわかんないのじゃ
I don't know the city.
朝里、めっちゃ朝関連のものが出てくるのじゃ
Asari... a lot of Asa-related things are coming up.
どこ？
Where?
小樽、小樽？
Otaru? Otaru?
確かにこっちもあったわ、朝里。朝里。
That's right, there was Asari over here too. Asari.
ギリ小樽か
Barely Otaru?
朝里町
Asaricho
で、ええ、朝里一丁目の18じゃところ
And, uh, Asari 1-chome 18...
あ、ここ分かりづらいのじゃ
Ah, this is hard to understand.
朝里一丁目
Asari 1-chome.
朝里一丁目、一丁目の18、18が多分ここで
Asari 1-chome, 1-chome 18, 18 is probably here...
18がSE E方向にあるから
And 18 is in the SE direction, so...
SE E
SE
で、グレースマンション
And Grace Mansion...
道の方角はNEW
The direction of the road is NE-SW.
NESW
こっから苦手なのじゃ
From here on, I'm bad at it.
レスポン
Respon-
えっと
Um...
ここに団地が、団地あったよね、団地
There's a housing complex here. There was one, right?
この辺じゃとわし苦手なんだよね、こっから絞るの
From around here, I'm bad at narrowing it down.
絞るの、こっから絞るの苦手なのじゃ
Narrowing it down... I'm bad at narrowing it down from here.
どこ？こっからがわかんないのじゃ
Where? I don't know from here.
ここの名前何だっけ？
What was the name here again?
よいしょ
Yoisho.
市営住宅
Municipal housing.
市営住宅病院、これじゃろ？
Municipal housing hospital, is this it?
市営住宅
Municipal housing.
これか
This?
この辺か
Around here?
市営住宅！惜しいのじゃ！
Municipal housing! So close!
ゲスト！のじゃ！
Guess! Noja!
難しかったのじゃ！
It was difficult!
小樽じゃった！
It was Otaru!
こっちだと思ってけど
I thought it was this way, but...
南に見えてた山が余市だけだった可能性ありなのじゃ
There's a possibility the mountain visible to the south was Yoichi.
惜しいのじゃ！
So close!
やっぱりいっぱい進んで情報を得るのが大事
As expected, it's important to advance a lot and get information.
小樽をなかなか見つけられなかったのじゃ
I couldn't find Otaru easily.
惜しいのじゃ！
So close!
次いくのじゃ！
Moving on to the next!
よいしょ
Yoisho.
雪が降りそうなのじゃ
It looks like it's going to snow.
鳥取県
Tottori Prefecture.
鳥取県はね
Tottori Prefecture...
こっち側雪降るからね
It snows on this side, you see.
鳥取県
Tottori Prefecture.
うーん、どっち行くのがいいかな？
Hmm, which way should I go?
1回こういうときは下るのじゃ
When this happens, you go down once.
下ってみますのじゃ
I'll try going down.
よいしょ
Yoisho.
めっちゃ雪降りそうな地域
An area where it looks like it will snow a lot.
川端
Kawabata.
これは会社名かな？
Is this a company name?
そして、こっち行ってみるか
And let's try going this way.
よいしょ
Yoisho.
進んでみるのじゃ。住宅住宅、住宅なのかな？
Let's advance. Housing, housing, is it housing?
なんて雪降りそうだと思ったか、こういうポールが立ってるところは雪がここまで積もるトコな気がするのじゃ
Why did I think it looked like snow? Places with poles like this feel like places where snow piles up high.
雪が積もったときも駐車場がどこかわかるように多分ポールが立ってるはずなのじゃ
There are probably poles so you know where the parking lot is even when snow piles up.
うーん、住宅街を進むのじゃ
Hmm, proceeding through a residential area.
あ、どっちから来たかわかんなくなっちゃった
Ah, I don't know which way I came from anymore.
こっち？
This way?
こっちか
Or this way?
あ、道っぽいのに出た
Ah, I came out onto what looks like a road.
なんか町の名前が書いてない、鳥取県
The town name isn't written, Tottori Prefecture.
鳥取県なのだじゃ
It's Tottori Prefecture.
鳥取県でW方面に、これはちょっとした山
In Tottori Prefecture, toward the W direction, this is a small mountain.
ここ、ここなんか高度高そう、高度高そうに見えるのじゃ
Here, this looks high in altitude, looks high in altitude.
あ、でも道路番号あるのじゃ
Ah, but there's a road number.
県道52号、江府町
Prefectural Route 52, Kofu-cho.
江府町
Kofu-cho.
江府町、江府町って何？
Kofu-cho, what is Kofu-cho?
江府町、県道52号を探すのじゃ！
Search for Kofu-cho, Prefectural Route 52!
これの探すのめっちゃ苦手なのじゃ！
I'm really bad at finding this!
わし道探すのめっちゃ苦手なのじゃ、道路
I'm really bad at finding roads!
江府町を探すのじゃ
Search for Kofu-cho.
52、52
52, 52.
道路番号じゃわかんないのじゃ
I can't tell from the road number.
道路番号から探すのすごい苦手なのじゃ
I'm really bad at searching from road numbers.
江府町あった！江府町吉原
Kofu-cho found! Kofu-cho Yoshiwara
あった！吉
Found! Yoshi-
どこかな？
Where is this?
52に
Route 52...
52、52がここなのじゃ。
Route 52 is right here.
で
And
よし。
Alright.
で中でも結構住宅、住宅より…
And among these, rather than houses...
うん。
Yeah.
そして田んぼ、田んぼ。
And paddy fields, paddy fields.
なんか建物もちゃんとね、見つけたい。
I want to properly find some buildings too.
なんか、道の探すより文字探すほうが多分得意。
Somehow, finding text is probably better for me than finding roads.
こっちはあんまりなさそうだから、家がいっぱいあるほういくのじゃ。
This way doesn't seem to have much, so I'll go where there are lots of houses.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
ほかに何かヒント欲しいな。
I want some other hints.
ヒント欲しいな。
I want a hint.
なんか建、建造物、建造物とかください。
Like, buildings, give me some buildings.
建造物、でっかい建、建造物くださいのじゃ。
Give me a big building, please.
あ、なんかあった。
Ah, there's something.
あ、ここもしや町と町のさかいめ？
Ah, is this perhaps the border between towns?
え、町村？
Eh, town/village?
ほう、ほうきちょう、ほうきちょう？
Hoki-cho, Hoki-cho?
何町？
What town?
ここ、の間、ここと言えの間じゃから…
Between here, since it's between here and here...
え、町と…これほうき…
Eh, town and... this Hoki...
間、間なのじゃ、間じゃから…
Between, it's between, since it's between...
ここのどっかかとは思う。
I think it's somewhere around here.
こっちのほうな気がする。こっちよりな気がするのじゃ。
I feel like it's this way. I feel like it's closer to this side.
でも電車なかったから、こっからここまでのどっかのさかいめなんじゃが…
But since there was no train, it's some border from here to here...
やっぱ高度はめちゃくちゃ高そう。
As expected, the altitude looks extremely high.
高度はめちゃくちゃ高そうなのじゃ。
It looks like the altitude is extremely high.
52、52、52はこれ。
52, 52, 52 is this.
このへんなのじゃ、52。
It's around here, 52.
で、初期地点どこじゃったかの。
And, where was the starting point again?
あ、結構くねくねしてるとこ。
Ah, a place with quite a few twists and turns.
結構くねくねめのところ、前…
A pretty twisting place, in front of...
これ前谷川？これ前谷川なのかな？
Is this Maetanigawa? Is this Maetanigawa?
結構くねくねめの奥の方から来たからこのへんおいとくか。
Since I came from deep in the twists and turns, I'll place it around here.
うん、もう18秒しかない。
Yeah, there's only 18 seconds left.
とっとり。
Tottori.
最初の写真のとこ、え、N…3本道だから、どこじゃろうな、わかんないのじゃ。
The initial photo's place, eh, N... It's a 3-way intersection, so where could it be, I don't know.
いっと、このへんじゃない？
Wait, isn't it around here?
来たのじゃー！
I found it!
げすなのだー！
Guessed it!
52、県道52号の近くの北側こっち向きでこういう道の形のところを探したのじゃ。
I looked for a place with this road shape, facing north near Prefectural Route 52.
やったのじゃー！
I did it!
でも5K取れたけど6メートルじゃったのじゃ。
But even though I got 5K, it was 6 meters off.
やったのじゃー！
I did it!
次いくのじゃ。
Moving on to the next one.
よいしょ。
Alright.
小林町、これは中部電力なのかな。
Kobayashi-cho, is this Chubu Electric Power?
小林町。
Kobayashi-cho.
どっち進もうかな、こっちになんか看板がある。
Which way should I go, there's some sign over here.
小林町、小林町。
Kobayashi-cho, Kobayashi-cho.
小林町。
Kobayashi-cho.
あ、青看板みっけなのかな。
Ah, I found a blue sign.
国道1号、鹿間、634。
Route 1, Shikama, 634.
鹿間、鹿間。
Shikama, Shikama.
鹿間、鹿間、鹿間。
Shikama, Shikama, Shikama.
鹿間なんか聞いたことあるような…
Shikama, sounds like I've heard of it before...
小林町探すのじゃ、えっと、三重の県道634号。
I'll look for Kobayashi-cho, um, Mie Prefectural Route 634.
634号…
Route 634...
44、国道44と…
44, National Route 44 and...
国道から探すのがいいのじゃ。
It's better to search from national routes.
国道探そう、国道どこ？
Let's find the national route, where is it?
国道の間…
Between national routes...
国道じゃ、国道1、国道1、44があったのじゃ。
National route, Route 1, Route 1, 44 was there.
44と634が交差するとこ、このへんな気がするのじゃ。
Where 44 and 634 intersect, I feel like it's around here.
632もあるし。
There's also 632.
634、634と44が交差するのはこのへんかな？
Where 634 and 44 intersect, is it around here?
小林町、小林町来たのじゃ。
Kobayashi-cho, I came to Kobayashi-cho.
小林町でレスポンス点に戻ると…
Returning to the response point in Kobayashi-cho...
あれ、どこから来たっけ？
Wait, where did I come from?
小林町…
Kobayashi-cho...
の？
Huh?
こっち行ったっけ？
Did I go this way?
うん
Yeah.
小林町の……よいしょ。
Kobayashi-cho's... phew.
よいしょ。
Phew.
ああ、さっきどうやって、どの道から来たのか忘れちゃったのじゃ。
Ah, I forgot which road I came from earlier.
じゃあ、
Well then,
よいしょ。
phew.
記憶力がね、全然ないからの。
My memory is just completely nonexistent.
なんか、住所とか書いてくれてたらいいんじゃが。
It'd be nice if they wrote down the address or something.
小林町自治会。
Kobayashi-cho Neighborhood Association.
でも小林町って書いてあったからきっとこのへんのどっかな気はしているのじゃ。
But it said Kobayashi-cho, so I feel it must be somewhere around here.
え、国道
Uh, National Route...
何号と何号？634と44が交わるところに行って、
What numbers? Going to where Route 634 and 44 intersect,
のじゃ。
you see.
こっち行ったっけ？
Did I go this way?
えの？
Huh?
こっち行った気がする最初。
I feel like I went this way at first.
小林町しか書いてないのじゃ。
It only says Kobayashi-cho.
小山田総合医療福祉センター。小山田記載医療グループ小山田福祉医療施設
Oyamada General Medical Welfare Center. Oyamada medical group, Oyamada welfare medical facility...
が近くにあるっぽい
seems to be nearby,
のじゃ。それを探すか。
so let's look for that.
どこ？
Where?
ないのじゃ。
It's not here.
あ、ここをみたのか。
Ah, did I look here?
そこ、
There...
あれ？どこ行った？
Huh? Where'd I go?
さっきの青看板、これ。
The blue sign from earlier, this one.
この青看板を、たぶんさっき見て、
I probably saw this blue sign earlier,
これ、これを、違う！
this, this... no!
違うやつなのじゃ。44、634。
It's a different one. 44, 634.
違うのじゃ。まあここで合わせるか。
It's different. Well, let's match it here.
44と634。
44 and 634.
44と634、
44 and 634,
で、どっから来たわし？
And where did I come from?
それが分かんないのじゃ。どっから来たか分かんないのじゃ。
I don't know. I don't know where I came from.
で、これが裏に見えたのじゃ。
And this appeared in the back.
本当に苦手なのじゃ、そういうの！
I'm really bad at those kinds of things!
本当にそういうの苦手なのじゃ！
I'm really bad at things like that!
方角苦手なのじゃ！
I'm bad with directions!
方角がめちゃくちゃ苦手。
I'm terrible with directions.
方角自信なしなのじゃ。
I have no confidence in directions.
えーっと、
Um...
N、Nに進んだ。
I went N, N.
え、むずい！
Uh, this is hard!
ねぇ、詰まったのじゃ！助けておのれら！
Hey, I'm stuck! Help me, you guys!
分かんなくなっちゃった！
I don't understand anymore!
分かんなくなっちゃったのじゃ！
迷子になっちゃった！
I became lost!
ちょ、好きな方向進んでみるか。
Let's try going in my favorite direction.
いったんね？
For now?
ああ、また違う道が現れた。
Ah, another different road appeared.
また違う道が……
Another different road...
ねぇ、住所、住所をおうちに書いて、おうちに住所書いてほしいのじゃ！
Hey, write the address on your house, I want you to write the address on your house!
どこなのじゃー！
Where is this?!
にゃい。にゃいです。
Meow. Meow.
もう一回行くか。よいしょ。
Let's go again. Phew.
これね？これが、今見た？えー、
This? This, did I just see? Um...
あ、あれ？戻ってきた。国道1号、戻ってきたのじゃ。
Huh? I came back. National Route 1, I came back.
ここ、ここ、ここね？
Here, here, here?
ここね？戻ってきた。え、戻ってきた？
Here? I came back. Huh, I came back?
なんで戻ってくるのじゃ？
Why am I coming back?
何が起きているのじゃ？
What is happening?
駐車場。
Parking lot.
今見えてるのはきっとこれなのだじゃ、駐車場。うん。
What I see now must be this, a parking lot. Yeah.
そして、44、Eと44、
And 44, East and 44,
あ、やばい。
Ah, oh no.
ちょ、わかんないから、わかんないから、いたなかいい感じの住宅地にさしてもらうじゃ。ちょわかんない、このへん。
I don't know, so let's drop into a nice residential area. I don't know, around here.
こっちじゃったーー！
It was this way!
した！南だった！南だったのじゃ！北の方行っちゃった！
South! It was south! It was south! I went north!
方角めっちゃ苦手。
I'm super bad with directions.
どっから来たか逆算、ちょっとそれやるのじゃ。次それやるのじゃ。
Let's calculate backwards from where I came. Let's do that next.
なんかこの細かいのがすごい苦手で、
I'm really bad at these detailed things,
薬の青木、見てなかったのじゃ。
I didn't see Kusuri no Aoki.
残念でした。
Too bad.
なんか時間が長ければ長いほどむずいのじゃ。
The longer the time, the harder it gets.
ゲスしてたのじゃ。北に向かってた。
I had guessed. I was heading north.
なんかどっちの方角、なんか、わし地図めっちゃ苦手で、
Which direction, you know, I'm really bad at maps,
ジオゲッサウ好きなんだけども、ジオゲッサウ好きなんだ けど、あの、
I love GeoGuessr, but, you know,
なんていうんじゃ？
how should I say?
普通にリアルでお外を全然歩けなくて、
In real life, I can't walk outside at all,
歩くときの地図は読めないのじゃ。なぜなら方角がわかんないのじゃ。
and I can't read maps when walking. Because I don't know directions.
自分 がどっちに進んでるのかわかんなくて、
I don't know which way I'm heading,
このマップは難易度どれぐらい？
so what's the difficulty of this map?
このマップは難易度というか、その日本公式マップで、
This map, or rather, the difficulty... it's the official Japan map,
日本のありとあらゆる場所が収録されていて、あの、ポーンって、ポーンって日本のどこかに落とされるマップ
where every possible place in Japan is recorded, and you get dropped somewhere in Japan with a pop.
なのだじゃ。あずき先輩とかがよくやっていらっしゃるマップは、その、例えばホロメン用オリジナルマップみたいな、その作成したマップ
Maps like Azuki-senpai often play are custom maps made for Holomem,
なんだが、結構ランダム要素が強い。
but this has strong random elements.
いや、地図苦手なのだじゃ。
Man, I'm bad at maps.
俯瞰（ふかん）で捉える、俯瞰で捉えるのがたぶんできないのじゃ、全然。
I probably can't grasp things from a bird's-eye view at all.
全然かんないのじゃ。
I totally don't get this.
この辺んまっぷはちょっと今使っていいかみたいな、そ、あの
I'm not sure if I can use this map right now, like, uh,
今日そもそもあの機材トラブルでゲーム変えたから、どのマップ使っていいかちょっとまだ確認が取れてなくて
Today, since I changed games due to equipment trouble, I haven't fully confirmed which map I should use.
今日は公式の日本のマップだけで遊ぶつもり。
So today I plan to play using just the official Japan map.
離島も出るのじゃ！離島も出ますのじゃ！
Remote islands will appear too! Remote islands will appear too!
山の中落とされると詰むのじゃ、ガチで。
If you get dropped in the middle of a mountain, you're totally screwed, seriously.
ちょ、いった、いった、いった、1分で、いった1分で短めでやってもいい？
Wait, once, once, once, in one minute, can I do it shortly in one minute?
なんかジオゲッサー遊ぶとき、その画面酔いするタイプではし
When playing GeoGuessr, I'm not the type who gets motion sick, so—
わし画面酔いするタイプじゃから、なんて言うんだろ。
Wait, I am the type who gets motion sick, so how should I say it?
あんま移動しながらみたいなのはやったことないのじゃ。
I've never really done things like moving around while looking.
ちょっと短めで動かないでやってみようと思うのじゃ。うん。
So I think I'll try it briefly without moving. Yeah.
まあ、動かなかったら時間なんでもいいか。時間制限なしで動かないでやってみようと思うのじゃ。
Well, if I don't move, any time is fine, right? I think I'll try doing it without moving, with no time limit.
動かないと酔わなくて楽なのじゃ。
If I don't move, I don't get dizzy, which is nice.
動かないと、047、047って千葉だっけ？
If I don't move... 047, was 047 Chiba?
千葉だとかだったような記憶あり。
I have a memory that it was Chiba or something.
千葉県立柏、柏、柏がね、確かね、千葉、なんかめちゃ情報多くない？
Chiba Prefectural Kashiwa... Kashiwa, Kashiwa has, right, Chiba... isn't there a ton of info?
情報多いのも逆に苦手なのじゃ、わし。
Conversely, I'm bad at when there's too much info.
逆に情報多いと頭バグるのじゃ。柏陵高等学校。
Conversely, when there's too much info, my brain bugs out. Kashiwa Ryo High School.
それを探すのじゃ。
I'll search for that.
ああ、情報量が多いのじゃ。柏陵、柏陵、柏、柏、柏。
Ah, there's a lot of information. Kashiwa Ryo, Kashiwa Ryo, Kashiwa, Kashiwa, Kashiwa.
どこじゃろ？高校。柏陵柏、柏柏、柏。
Where could it be? High school. Kashiwa Ryo Kashiwa, Kashiwa Kashiwa, Kashiwa.
広い目でで見てもわかんないかな。
Even looking broadly, I wonder if I can't tell.
これそもそも北なのか？
Is this even north?
松戸中央、でも自動車学校、社会駅、東口、社会駅あんま関係ないかな。なんていうんだろ。
Matsudo Chuo... but driving school, Sakai Station, east exit... Sakai Station might not be related. What is it?
他に情報はなさそう。学校で探すしかないの？
No other info seems likely. Do I have to search by school?
学校探すかあ！学校探すの難しいのじゃ。
Search for the school! Searching for schools is difficult.
ローラー、柏ローラー。でもちょっと時間が
Roller, Kashiwa roller. But time...
時間がかかりそうだから、ずばっと決めちゃいたいんだが。
It looks like it'll take time, so I want to decide definitively.
時間区っとけばよかったな。こういう答えが載ってるやつって
I should have blocked out the time. Things like this that have answers listed...
答えが載ってるやっって
Things that have answers listed...
無限に時間使っちゃうからな。
...end up taking infinite time.
松戸社会駅とか書いてあった。この辺の間と予想。
It said Matsudo Sakai Station or something. I guess it's somewhere around here.
予想だが。ちょ、んーん？
That's my guess, but... wait, huh?
沼るからやめるのじゃ！
I'll quit because I'm getting bogged down!
堺があった！堺駅があった！
Sakai was there! Sakai Station was there!
堺駅を従えばよかったのじゃ。
I should have followed Sakai Station.
堺駅自動車学校の表示のとこに書いてあった。
It was written where the Sakai Station driving school sign was.
なんかそういう広告って本物のときと本物じゃないときがある。
Some ads like that have times when they're real and times when they're fake.
偽物と思ったら本物だったのじゃ。
I thought it was fake, but it was real.
失礼しましたのじゃ。
My apologies.
次いくのじゃ。
Next one.
なんじゃ？西サツ内？
What's this? Nishi-Satsunai?
なんか北海道っぽくない？
Doesn't it feel kind of like Hokkaido?
なんかめっちゃ北海道っぽいのじゃ。
It feels super Hokkaido-ish.
北海道のなんかどの辺じゃろな？
Whereabouts in Hokkaido could it be?
寸動東6線。
Sundo Higashi 6-sen.
寸動東6線。なんか道が開けすぎな気もしつつ。
Sundo Higashi 6-sen. Also feels like the roads are a bit too open.
牧場、牧場あるし。ね。
Ranches, there are ranches. Yeah.
そっから寸動。
From there, Sundo.
ええ、どこかのなんか体感ね？
Uh, somewhere, like, my intuition?
体感こういう、こういう、こういうとこなんって気がするのじゃ。
My intuition says it's somewhere like this, this, this.
寸動はわし知らないんじゃが。
I don't know Sundo though.
西サツ内。
Nishi-Satsunai.
ちょ、山見るか一旦。山山。
Wait, let's look at the mountains for a moment. Mountains, mountains.
でも見づらいな。
Hard to see though.
西に山。
Mountain to the west.
北はなし。
North, none.
南もなし、うっすら。
South, none, faintly.
西に結構ちゃんと山が、ある、な。
To the west, there are quite proper mountains.
西にちゃんとう山があるな。なんか、いったんこの辺置くか。
There are proper mountains to the west. Like, let's place it around here for now.
まあこの、あ、本当だ書いてある。
Well, this... ah, true, it's written.
中
Naka-
初っ端。
Right off the bat.
書いてあったのじゃ。
Wait, it was written.
なんか帯広らへんかなあとは思ったのじゃ。
I thought it was around Obihiro, though.
こっちでした。
It was over here.
もっと南だったのじゃ。
It was more south, huh?
北海道広いから絞るのむずい之じゃ。
Hokkaido is so big, it's hard to narrow down.
うーん、山の方向とかで分かるのじゃ。
Hmm, you can tell by the mountain directions, right?
確かに。え、めっちゃ山近くない?
True, isn't it super close to the mountains?
日高山脈だったのじゃあれ。
It was the Hidaka Mountains, wasn't it?
気づかなかった。
I didn't even notice.
日高山脈。
Hidaka Mountains...
空港が近くにあったんじゃん。
The airport was close by, huh?
次行くのじゃ。
Let's go to the next one!
よいしょ。
Here we go.
めっちゃ住宅街。
Man, it's a residential area.
めっちゃ住宅街なのだ。
It's totally a residential area.
九州っぽくない?
Feels kind of like Kyushu, doesn't it?
日口し?
Hikuchi...
九州なのだ。
It's Kyushu, huh?
日口市どこだっけ?日口市。
Where was Hikuchi City again? Hikuchi City...
日口市の。
Hikuchi City...
これはなんじゃ?
What is this?
八幡宮。車石八幡宮。
Hachiman Shrine? Kurumaishi Hachiman Shrine?
車石八幡宮。
Kurumaishi Hachiman Shrine...
車石八幡宮があるのじゃ。
There's a Kurumaishi Hachiman Shrine.
でもそれはちょっとわかんないのじゃ。
But I don't really get it.
ちっちゃすぎる。
It's too small.
し、まあ、きっくし、うーん。
Shi... well, Kikuchi... Shi... hmm.
あとは山、山も見えないの。
Also, I can't see any mountains either.
熊本、なんか九州電力の電柱をこういう形にしてるのじゃ。
Kumamoto... it's like they're making Kyushu electric power poles like this.
うーん。
Hmm.
でも結構奥まったところにあってもおかしくないような気がしていて、
Even if it's deep inside, it feels like it could be there, doesn't it?
奥まったとこにあってもおかしくない気がしていて、
It feels like it could be in a remote place.
何八幡宮?車石。車石。
Any Hachiman Shrine, Kurumaishi... Kurumaishi...
ま、見つかんないからこの辺置くのじゃ。
Can't find it, so I'll just place it around here.
よいしょ。
Here we go.
うん。
Yep.
まあ、もうちょい南。
Well, a bit more south.
もうちょい南じゃったか。
Was it a bit more south?
でもまあ、ほんとだ車石八幡書いてある。
Wait, it actually says Kurumaishi Hachiman.
書いてあるのじゃ。
It is written!
なんか、でも市から山はこれぐらいの距離ってのはおよそ合ってたのじゃ。
Wait, if it's Shi, then mountains...
なのじゃ。
Right?
電柱でし、なんか地方大体分かるから、
With telephone poles, you can sort of tell the region.
お主らあの写真上げちゃダメだよ。
You guys shouldn't upload photos, you know?
お主ら散歩中とかに写真上げちゃダメなのだ。
You guys shouldn't post photos while taking a walk.
散歩中に写真上げると簡単に特定されちゃうのじゃ。
If you post photos during a walk, you can easily be identified.
ちなみにわしもちょっと怖い思いをしたことがあるのじゃ。
By the way, I've also had some scary experiences.
から気をつけるのじゃお主らも。
So, you guys should be careful too.
次行くのじゃ。
Let's go to the next one.
よいしょ。
Here we go.
あー、あんまり情報がなさそうな予感。
Ah, doesn't look like there's much info.
なんか、わかんないのは本当にわかんないのじゃ。
If I don't know, I really don't know.
立ってか。
Standing, huh?
これわしあんまかんないのじゃ。
I really don't know about this.
ぼかされてる。
It's blurred out.
ぼかされてるのじゃ。
It's blurred out, huh?
何電力?教えてほしいのじゃ。
What power company? Please tell me!
この太いのどこだっけ?忘れちゃったのじゃ。
Where was this thick one again? I forgot.
え、これわしわかんないかも。
Wait, I might not know this!
これわかんないからこのみかんゲストするしかない。これみかんのかな?
Since I don't know, I can only guess it's mandarin orange.
(笑い)
Hehehe.
これ、これみかんのかな?なんなんじゃ?これなんとと思う。
Is this, is this mandarin? What is it? That's what I think.
でもなんか山とかない、こっちにあるか。
Wait, there are no mountains, or are they on this side?
南に、南に山があるか。
There are mountains to the south, maybe?
これ全然わかんないのじゃ。
I have no idea at all.
わかんないけど、
I don't know, but...
これなんだろ。
What on earth is this?
でも窓はどうなっているこれ?
Wait, how is the window set up here?
ぶ厚くもみえてしまうどうしても。
Even though corrugated metal is visible, no matter what.
ぶ厚めの窓に見えちゃうんじゃが、違うかも。
It might be visible through a thicker window, though.
これはこういう問題が出たらもう潔く諦めてるのじゃわからないから。
If this kind of problem comes up, I'm already giving up easily because I don't know.
ちょっと情報がないか見たいけど、見るだけ見るか。
I want to see if there's no info, but should I just look, or...
見るだけ見るか。
Should I just look?
こういう時は、こういう時は兵庫とかに岡山とか。
When it's like this, when it's like this, it could be Hyogo or Okayama.
岡山とかにするのじゃ。
Okayama or somewhere.
でも結構、ちょい寒そう。
It's a bit cold, though.
これってなんか二重窓が本当に二重っぽいのか、ただそういうデザインなのかがわかんないことがあり。
Is this double-paned window really double-paned, or is it just a design? I can't tell.
一旦この辺に置くのじゃ。一旦この辺に置くのじゃ。
I'll just put it around here for now.
名古屋!
Nagoya!
中部なんだ!
Chubu!
全然わかんなかった!
I had no idea at all!
え!めっちゃ名古屋市!
Whoa! Nagoya City!
ちょっと見ていい?
Let me check.
全然わかんなかったのじゃ。稲沢市。
I had no idea at all! Inae Town.
え、全然わかんなかったのじゃ。ちょっと動いていい?
I had no idea at all! Let me move a bit.
本当にわかんなかった。
I really had no idea.
本当に全くわかんなかった。
I had absolutely no idea.
本当にわかんなかった。
I really had no idea.
はえー。
Whoa.
ここまで来たらね。
If you get this far...
ここまできたら見えるんじゃが。
If you come this far, you can see it, though.
本当に全然わかんなかった。
I really had no idea.
ジオゲッサーをやっぱ一問一答だから
Since GeoGuessr is basically just Q&A,
次この景色が出たら、名古屋にすることにするのじゃ。
next time this scenery comes up, I'll make it Nagoya.
全然わかんなかったのじゃ！
I had no idea!
備前焼？
Bizen-yaki pottery?
あ、書いてあるじゃん。吉備中央。
Oh, it's written right there! Kibichuo.
めっちゃ書いてあるのじゃ。
It says so much!
国道53、吉備中央、この辺なのだ。
Route 53, Kibichuo. Around here, I guess.
まあ、なんか中国電力で、このまま置いとちゃか。
Well, Chugoku Electric Power... Let's just leave it at this.
53号を71、こういうの探すの苦手なのだ。
53 and 71...
こういうの探すの苦手なのだ。
Finding things like this is hard for me.
71と53が交わる所、こっちとか。
Where 71 and 53 intersect...
こういうのわかんないのじゃ。川なくね？
I don't get this. No river?
川なくね？
Oh, there is no river.
旧国名なのだ。山、山がめっちゃ見える、山の中。
It's a valley, I guess? Mountains! Lots of mountains visible, deep in the mountains.
これが国道53号。
This is Route 53.
ここからわかんないのじゃ。北。
I can't tell from here. North.
よかった！こっちでした。こっちでしたのじゃ。
Oh, it was this way! It was this way!
なんか青看板の見方とか、方位とかが全然わかんなくて
I'm really bad at reading blue signs and figuring out directions.
全然わかんなくて、地図苦手、
I'm really bad at maps,
地図苦手だから地図以外の情報で見るのじゃ。
so I look for things other than the map.
交わるところがあるならちょっと前。確かに。確かに！
If there's an intersection, a bit earlier... True!
次行くのじゃ。あ、結果を見る。
Let's check the results.
2万11点。
20,211 points.
一回ちょっと途中でね、ここここね、
Wait, halfway through...
美濃加茂市、ここで大ミスをしてしまい、敗北したのじゃ。
Minokamo, I made a huge mistake here.
地図がね、わかるようになったらもっと上手になると思うのじゃ。
If I get better at maps, I'll get even better at this.
ね、川なかったよね？
See, there was no river, right?
川なかったなってのを思って、こんなでかい川見えなかったよねって、そう思うのじゃ。
I kept thinking, "There's no way such a big river was there."
そう、青看板とかはやっぱあずき先輩って地理めっちゃ強いから
Well, as for blue signs, Azuki-senpai is super strong at geography,
そういう地理系の知識とかだともう全然全然もう勝てません。もう全く全く
so I can never win against that kind of geography knowledge.
全く相手になりません、わし弱すぎて。
I'm no match for her, I'm way too weak.
名古屋通くんなのじゃ。
Nagoya is my turf, though.
回するのじゃ。
I'll do it again!
ちょ、次ちょっとちゃんと時間絞ってやるか。
Next time, I should set a proper time limit.
時間絞らないと一生できちゃうのじゃ。
If I don't set a time limit, I could do this forever.
もう1分でやっていい？
Can I do it in 1 minute?
道路の太さも違ったよね。
The road widths were different too, weren't they?
そう、地理の勉強もちゃんしたいのじゃ。
I want to study geography properly, too.
わしまだ都道府県しか知らなくて、市とかは全然知らないから
I only really know prefectures, not even specific cities.
なんかあんま動画見て勉強とかもそこいたくさんしてるわけじゃないから
I haven't watched that many videos to study or anything,
今後ね、あずき先輩が戦っていただけるって時には、ちょっと1ヶ月ぐらい特訓して遊びたいと思いますのじゃ。
so next time Azuki-senpai wants to play, I want to train hard for a month first!
なんか一人でさやってるとさ
You know, when you do this alone,
なんか途中でもういいかなってなっちゃう。
you start feeling like, "I'm kind of done with this," halfway through.
人と遊びたいのじゃ、やっぱ。
I want to play with others, I guess.
人と遊びたい、で、でもなんか定期的にね、帰ってくるけど。
Even though I come back regularly.
人と遊びたいから
I want to play with people, so
あずき先輩が遊んでくれるの嬉しいのじゃ。
it makes me happy when Azuki-senpai plays with me.
南岡、岡じゃん。岡なんじゃが、
Minamigaoka? It's Oka, I guess.
それ以外のことがわかんないのじゃ。
I don't know anything else about it.
またドミスの可能性あり。
Could be Domisu again.
このポールキーは覚えてないのじゃ。
I don't remember this utility pole.
どこなのだ？教えてほしいのじゃ。
Where is this? Please tell me!
そう、山に住んでた時期長いからね。
I used to live in the mountains for a long time, so...
ちょ、コーチングしてもよちょっと置くか。1回どっか置くか。
Let's do some coaching. Let's place it somewhere.
岡、岡がめっちゃいます。
Oka, Oka is everywhere.
ド外れの可能性あり。南。
Could be way off. Minami.
ちょ、わからんのじゃ。
I have no idea.
ド外れなのだ！
It was way off!
神奈川でしたのじゃ。
It was Kanagawa!
神奈川でしたのじゃ。神奈川はわかった？
It was Kanagawa. Kanagawa, got it?
なんで神奈川わかったの？
Why did I know it was Kanagawa?
神奈川わかんなかった。
I couldn't tell if it was Kanagawa.
書いてあったかな、どっかに。
Wonder if it was written somewhere.
白い壁の家って神奈川なの？
Are houses with white walls in Kanagawa?
なんかあんま神奈川かわかんなかったのじゃ。
Somehow I couldn't really tell if it was Kanagawa.
神奈川ってこんな景色なんなの？
Is Kanagawa really this kind of scenery?
情報がありませんでした。
There was no information.
車のナンバーはジオゲッサーぼかされてて見えませんのじゃ。
The car plates are blurred out in GeoGuessr so I can't see them.
なんか、こっちらへんの香り
It has that kind of vibe around here...
ね、大体あんな感じの景色。
Yeah, pretty much that kind of scenery.
ちなみに、山っぽいのが見えなぃのじゃ。
Incidentally, you can't see anything mountain-like.
新参は板金？
"Shinsanwa Sheet Metal"?
新参は板金。
Shinsanwa Sheet Metal.
え、これ、これこっちじゃないの？
Huh, isn't this... isn't this this way?
こっちとかじゃないのじゃ。
Isn't it over here?
富山な気がするのじゃ。
I have a feeling it's Toyama.
富山っぽい。
It looks like Toyama.
富山っぽい空もなんか曇りっぽいし。
The sky looks like Toyama, kind of cloudy too.
でも山とか全然見えないからちょっとわからないの。
But you can't see mountains at all so I'm not sure.
意外と海方面とか海近かとか。
Surprisingly toward the ocean or close to the sea...
のじゃ。
...you know.
高岡市か。
Takaoka City?
富山ではあったけど。
It was in Toyama though.
漢字、漢字苦手なのじゃ。
Kanji, I'm bad at kanji.
高岡市なのはじゃ、板金？
Takaoka City, is it... sheet metal?
板金って読むの？
Do you read it as "bankin"?
富山でしたのじゃ。
It was Toyama.
なぜ富山か。
Why Toyama?
なんか プレート横、全部横だから、あの、
Since the plates are all horizontal, um...
北陸電力だなと思って
I thought, ah, Hokuriku Electric Power...
なんとなくなのじゃ。で、あんま山が
Just a gut feeling. And not much mountain...
富山の南の方もっとちょい山が見えるけど、
Further south in Toyama you can see a bit more mountains,
あんま山が見えなかったからちょっと海らへんかなって思ったのじゃ。
but since I couldn't see many mountains, I thought maybe it was near the sea.
直線は全然詳しくないのじゃ。
I'm not familiar with vegetation at all.
植生はわかんないのじゃ。
I don't know about vegetation.
木が太い細いしかわかんないのじゃ。
I only know if trees are thick or thin.
次いくのじゃ。
Let's go to the next one.
ダイレックス。
Direx.
とす？
Tosu?
とすってどこだっけ？
Where is Tosu?
とすってどこだっけ？ちょっととすってとめ
Where is Tosu? Wait, Tosu...
いや、九州だ。九州。
No, it's Kyushu. Kyushu.
何が本当なのじゃ。
What is the truth?
「おはよう家族に挨拶 みんなにあいさつ」
[Sign: "Good morning, greet your family, greet everyone"]
なんじゃ。
What's this?
九州電力。とすめっちゃ聞いたことあると思うんだけどな。
Kyushu Electric Power. I feel like I've heard of Tosu a lot.
めっちゃ聞いたことある気がするんだが。
I feel like I've heard of it so much.
とす、とす。
Tosu, Tosu.
か、かふじたちょう？
Ka... Kafujita-cho?
かふじたちょう。
Kafujita-cho.
忘れたのじゃ。
I forgot.
探すのじゃ。とす、とすどこだっけな。
Let's find it. Tosu, where was Tosu again?
あっ、とすし！とすし！
Ah, Tosu City! Tosu City!
かふじたちょう。
Kafujita-cho.
かふじたちょうまで行けなかったのじゃ。
I couldn't reach Kafujita-cho.
このへんだった。ぎりぎり！
It was around here. Barely!
超ぎりぎり！
Super barely!
新鳥栖駅。
Shintosu Station.
そうか、新幹線通ってるからか。
Oh right, because the Shinkansen runs through.
なんか、久しぶりにやると、
Somehow, when I play after a long time,
地名とかも全部抜け落ちているのじゃ。
all the place names and everything completely slip my mind.
ふじ、かふじた、かふじ
Fuji, Kafujita, Kafuji...
かふじたちょうないよ、広げても。どこじゃ？
Kafujita-cho isn't there, even if I zoom out. Where is it?
書いてないのじゃ、かふじたちょう。
It's not written, Kafujita-cho.
西九州新幹線。そうそうそうそうそう！
West Kyushu Shinkansen. Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
これ、ここに通ってるのじゃ。
It passes right here.
新鳥栖。新鳥栖駅。
Shintosu. Shintosu Station.
Cいっぱい覚えたいな。
I want to memorize lots of city names.
まだ全部C覚えてないから、いつか全部覚えたいのじゃ。かとうし。
I haven't memorized all the city names yet, so someday I want to memorize them all. Kato City...
次！いしょ。
Next! Let's go.
ひろめ、広い景色。
Hirome, wide scenery.
広い景色なのだ。
It's a wide scenery.
広い空、焦げてるプレート。
Wide sky, scorched plates.
のじゃ。
...you know.
のじゃ？のじゃ？のじゃ？のじゃ？
You know? You know? You know? You know?
なんなのじゃ？
What is this?
九州とかな?
Kyushu or something?
広い。
It's wide.
山がある。西に?
There are mountains. To the west?
南にはない。
Not to the south.
これ何?白鳥?いろ白鳥?
What is this? Swans? Colored swans?
いや、北海道だ。北海道なのじゃ。
No, it's Hokkaido. It's Hokkaido.
北海道のどこかと言われると、え、本当に北海道?
When asked where in Hokkaido... eh, really Hokkaido?
わかんないのじゃ。
I don't know.
西に山?
Mountains to the west?
え、どこじゃろ?
Eh, where could it be?
うわーー！北海道当たってよかった！
Whoa! I'm so glad I guessed Hokkaido!
北海道当たってよかった！
I'm so glad I guessed Hokkaido!
全然分からなかったのじゃ。
I totally didn't know.
この辺白鳥?
Around here is swans?
へえー。
Huh.
なんか最初九州置いちゃったけど、北海道だったのじゃ。
I placed it in Kyushu at first, but it was Hokkaido.
ちゃんと見てなかったのじゃ。
I wasn't looking properly.
へえー、全然分からなかった！北海道のどこか分かるヒントあったかな?
Huh, I totally had no idea! Were there any hints telling me where in Hokkaido?
白鳥ってこの辺なのかな?
Is 'swan' around here?
伊達市。
Date City.
あれ?足動いとる?
Huh? Are the legs moving?
動いとる。
They're moving.
どうやってここの北海道の西? 南西に寄せられるんだろう?
How do you narrow it down to western, southwestern Hokkaido?
だって市、ここ当てられるヒントあったかな?
Date City, were there hints to guess here?
まあ、西、山、山山山。
Well, west, mountains, mountains mountains mountains.
うん、ちょっと難しいのじゃ。
Yeah, it's a bit difficult.
広いのは北海道。
The wide one is Hokkaido.
まあ、開けてはいるけど。
Well, it's open, but...
なんかこれめっちゃ北海道っぽい。
This feels super like Hokkaido.
これめっちゃ北海道っぽいのだじゃ。
ね、海沿いだったね。
Hey, it was along the coast.
ちょっと北海道って分かったのがギリギリだったのじゃ、あまりにも。
Realizing it was Hokkaido was super last minute.
カクカク。カクカク。
Choppy, choppy.
伊達市2個あるのじゃ?
Are there two Date Cities?
電圧スペーサーなくない?
Isn't there a voltage spacer?
や、あ、あるあるあるある！
Oh, ah, there are, there are!
あった！あったのだじゃ！めちゃ見逃してた！
There it is! It was there! I totally missed it!
これで北海道って言ったらちょっとおもろいのじゃ。ちょっとおもろいのじゃ。
If I said Hokkaido based on this, it'd be pretty funny.
マンホールが伊達市のデザイン?
Is the manhole Date City's design?
白鳥? 白鳥だと伊達市なのだじゃ?
Swan? If it's a swan, is it Date City?
え、可愛いから覚えよう。
Eh, it's cute so I'll memorize it.
白鳥のマンホールは伊達市のデザインっぽいのだじゃ。
Swan manholes seem to be Date City's design.
覚えよう可愛いから。
I'll memorize it because it's cute.
白鳥で有名? あ、有名なんだ。
Famous for swans? Ah, it's famous.
じゃあわし知らんかったのだじゃ。
Then I didn't know.
次を覚えるのだじゃ。
I'll memorize the next one.
次を覚えて次白鳥が出たらここに置くのだじゃ。
I'll memorize the next one and if a swan comes up next, I'll place it here.
書いてある? ちょ、それを見せてほしい。
Is it written? Cho, I want you to show me that.
本当だ！
Really!
ここに白鳥の背中に、これなんて読むんだ? あり、アリス? アリジュ? アリジュ?
On the back of the swan here, what do you read this? Ari, Alice? Ariju? Ariju?
ちょ、漢字自信なし。読み方教えてほしいのだじゃ。
Cho, no confidence in kanji. I want you to teach me how to read it.
読み方教えてほしいのだじゃ。アリジュ? アリジュ?
I want you to teach me how to read it. Ariju? Ariju?
アンジュ?
Anju?
なんて読むのだじゃ?
How do you read it?
いやでも確かに文字書いてあった。気づかなかったのだじゃ。
Well, indeed letters were written. I hadn't noticed.
おいしょ。
Heave-ho.
本当だ。
Really.
ウス? ウスっていうものじゃ? アリス? アリス? アリジュ? 何が本当? ウス山? あ、ウス?
Usu? Is it called Usu? Alice? Alice? Ariju? What's real? Usu Mountain? Ah, Usu?
あ、これウス山って読むんだ。
Ah, this is read as Mt. Usu.
ウス山。
Mt. Usu.
ウスって読むらしいのだじゃ。ウスチョウ。ウスチョウのマンホールは白鳥が要るのだじゃ。
It seems to be read as Usu. Usu Town. Usu Town's manholes have swans.
ウスチョウのマンホールは白鳥がいるのだじゃ。覚えたのだじゃ。
Usu Town's manholes have swans. I memorized it.
ありがとなのだじゃ。
Thanks.
次行くか。なのじゃ。
Shall we go next? Nono.
え?ゆめタウンある！
Eh? There's Youme Town!
西なのだじゃ。
It's west.
ゆめタウンある、ゆめタウン。
There's Youme Town, Youme Town.
ゆめタウンは西とか南な気がするのだじゃ。
I feel like Youme Town is in the west or south.
ゆめ...
Youme...
ええ、どこじゃろうな?
Eh, where could it be?
そっから、そっから先なんだよな。九州から先。
From there, it's beyond that. Beyond Kyushu.
九州から先。でも結構広めの道が有るそう。
Beyond Kyushu. But there seems to be a fairly wide road.
広めの道が有るそう。広めの道が有るそうだし、こっちの方に置いても怒られない気する。
There seems to be a wide road. There seems to be a wide road, and I feel like I won't get yelled at even if I place it this way.
山とかはちょっと見えないのだじゃ。
Mountains and stuff are kind of not visible.
山とかちょっと全然見えない。
Mountains and stuff are completely not visible.
見えないからなんとも言えないんじゃが。
Since they're not visible, I can't really say anything, but...
マンホールね、わしね、知らない、全然。
Manholes, you know, I don't know at all.
もっと北か！北九州！北九州だったのだじゃ！
Further north! Kitakyushu! It was Kitakyushu!
中国地方のほうが多い、それはそうなのだじゃ。中国地方に多いのだじゃ。
There are more in the Chugoku region, that's right. There are many in the Chugoku region.
遠賀町？
Onga-chō?
え、これわかるかも？
Eh, can I figure this out?
北、北の方に海の匂いする？こっちに海の匂いする？お主ら
North, does it smell like the ocean to the north? Does it smell like the ocean this way, guys?
結構海近なはずなんだが
It should be pretty close to the ocean, though.
海の匂いしないのじゃ？てんきがこの日悪いからかな
Doesn't it smell like the ocean? Maybe because the weather is bad today.
天気がよかったら海の匂いしたかも
If the weather had been nice, it might have smelled like the ocean.
ま、確かに言われてみれば、向こうに海がありますよって言われたら、あるような気も、あるような気もしなくもないくらい
Well, true, if you're told "there's the sea over there," it feels a bit like it... or at least not entirely unlike it.
遠賀？
Onga?
遠賀町？わ、遠賀町聞いたことある気がするのじゃ、遠賀町
Onga-chō? Ah, I feel like I've heard of Onga-chō.
海の匂いする、海の匂いするのじゃ
It smells like the ocean, it smells like the ocean.
なんか、不自然に高い建物とか山とかなくて、景色が開きすぎてると、めっちゃ海の匂いを感じ取っちゃうのじゃ。遠賀川
Like, when there are no unnaturally tall buildings or mountains, and the scenery is too open, you end up really feeling the smell of the ocean. Onga River.
かっこいいのじゃ、遠賀川。遠賀川なのだじゃ
It's cool, the Onga River. It's the Onga River.
そういうのが、あるんじゃの
So there are things like that.
最後に、なんか、動いたりするか
Finally, like, should I move around a bit?
ちょ、お主ら、わしにいつまで付き合ってくれる？わしにいつまで付き合ってくれる？
Hey guys, how long are you gonna stick with me?
お主らは、わしと共に、わしと共に、えこれ本物？
You guys, staying with me... wait, is this real?
わしと共に、過ごしてくれる？
Will you spend time together with me?
あの、時間制限なしで、時間制限なしで、やってみませんか
Um, without a time limit, without a time limit, won't we try that?
ちょっと、時間制限なしだと、ガチ一生地獄、一生地獄続いちゃうんじゃが
Wait, without a time limit, it would seriously be an endless hell...
あ、一生続かなそう！
Ah, looks like it won't last forever!
ありがたーーい！
So grateful!
ありがたいけど、携帯電話では番号は見てもわかんないのじゃ。
Grateful, but on a cell phone, you can't tell even if you look at the phone number.
市街局番号が欲しいのじゃ
I want the area code.
森、森工事
Mori, Mori Construction
森工事二丁目、何区？
Mori Construction 2-chome, which ward?
でも結構情報量多そうだから期待、期待できる、期待できるのじゃ
But since there seems to be a lot of info, I can have high expectations.
じゃ、この試合が最後だけど
Well, this match is the last one, but
この試合は、できるだけいっぱいやられたいように頑張りたいと思っておりますのじゃ
I'm hoping to do my absolute best and play as much as possible in this match.
お主を早く寝かしつけるのじゃ、わしが
I'm gonna put you to sleep early.
それでは、拝見させていただくのじゃ
Well then, let me take a look.
街並みを、街並みを
The townscape, the townscape.
こんな、大阪じゃろ？ヒット大阪じゃろ？
Like this, it's Osaka, right? Hit Osaka, right?
と思っているんじゃが、大阪だと思ってるんじゃが、頑張れ！頑張れごめん！頑張れごめん！頑張れ！
Is what I think, thinking it's Osaka, but—come on! Come on, sorry! Come on, sorry! Come on!
動く？動ける？あ動けた動けた動けた
Move? Can it move? Ah, it moved, it moved, it moved.
ちょ、情報、情報が、情報取りすぎて画面がカクついてるのじゃ
Wait, info, taking in too much info and lagging the screen.
ドカックスキ、ドカックスキ来た
Doka-kutsuki arrived.
朝日区？
Asahi-ku?
ちょっ、ちょっ、パソコン頑張るのじゃ！
Wait, wait, PC, hang in there!
カクカクなるのじゃ！カクカクなるのじゃ！ちょい！
It's lagging! It's lagging! Hey!
大阪市、絶対大阪なのじゃ
Osaka City, it's definitely Osaka.
で、朝日区、朝日区、朝日区知らないから探すのじゃ。朝日区ってどこじゃろうな
And Asahi-ku, I don't know Asahi-ku so I'm searching for it. Where on earth is Asahi-ku?
なんか大阪と思ったのは、関西電力で道がキュウキュウだったからなのだじゃ。道がキュウキュウだったから
Like, the reason I thought it was Osaka was because Kansai Electric Power and the streets were cramped.
朝日、朝日区、森工事。森工事二丁目
Asahi, Asahi-ku, Mori Construction. Mori Construction 2-chome.
難しいのじゃ、この、なんか、こういうさ、地図を見てさ、置けない、わし地図見て置けないんだよ、なんか。でも、どこじゃってなっちゃう
It's difficult, looking at a map like this and not being able to place it... I can't place it just looking at a map. But then I end up wondering "where is it?"
森工事、二丁目、一丁目
Mori Construction, 2-chome, 1-chome.
二丁目ない、二丁目ないのじゃ、一丁目しかないのじゃ
There's no 2-chome, there's only 1-chome.
一丁目、で一丁目以外ない
1-chome, and nothing other than 1-chome.
あ、二丁目、二丁目。21、21
Ah, 2-chome, 2-chome. 21, 21.
こういうの苦手、21、21
I'm bad at this kind of thing, 21, 21.
このへん？
Around here?
違うかも。
Maybe not.
で、リスポンに戻るのじゃ。
Now, let's return to the spawn point.
ここ、何か書いてあった気がするのじゃ。
I feel like something was written here.
森工事二丁目12...
Morikoji 2-chome 12...
森工事二丁目12が、えっと...
Morikoji 2-chome 12 is, um...
森工事二丁目12 ここかな？
Morikoji 2-chome 12, is it here?
森工事二丁目12
Morikoji 2-chome 12
二丁目
2-chome
二丁目 がさ、の範囲がどこまでかとかがさ
The range of 2-chome and stuff...
あ、全然わかんないんだよ。
Ah, I totally don't get it.
二丁目
2-chome...
このへんなのかな？
Is it around here?
森工事 こっちなのかな、それとも。
Morikoji, is it this way, or that?
それがね、よくわかんないのじゃ。
I don't really get that part.
どっちが森工事の二丁目なんじゃろ。
Which one is Morikoji 2-chome?
どこまでが一丁目なんじゃろ。
How far is 1-chome?
こっちかな二丁目。
This way might be 2-chome.
でも道、確かに道から特定するか。
But roads, let's identify from roads.
えーと、北を向いたときに、え、でもここ？
Um, when facing north, wait, but here?
ここか？
Here?
じゃあ道的にここだな。
Then geographically, it's here.
道的にここなのじゃ。
Geographically, it's here.
じゃあ寄せていきますのじゃ。
Then let's narrow it down.
えーっと、こっちで、こっちで こっちで
Um, this way, this way, this way...
え、このへんかな。
Eh, is it around here?
もうちょっとこっち？ 0メートルって難しいのじゃ。
A bit more this way? Zero meters is hard.
このへんかな？一旦このへんでいこうなのじゃ。
Around here? Let's go with this for now.
のじゃあ！
Yay!
0メートル無理なのじゃ！
Zero meters is impossible!
こっちであった。
It was this way.
こっちだったのじゃ。
新潟なのじゃ。
It's Niigata.
最後のこの0メートルに行くやつ。
The last one going to zero meters.
ちょっとお水入れたい。
I want to get some water.
0ゲース失敗なのじゃ。
0 GeoGuessr failure.
次、よいしょ。
Next, heave-ho.
ふーん、なかなかに開けた景色、これ絶対もう
Hmm, quite an open view, this definitely is...
これもう、
This already,
これもうさすがに北海道でいいのじゃ。
This is definitely Hokkaido.
さすがにもうこれは北海道でいいと思いますなのじゃ。
I think this is definitely Hokkaido.
北海道で、え、島松朝日町、
In Hokkaido, um, Shimamatsu Asahimachi,
島松朝日町を探すのじゃ。
Let's look for Shimamatsu Asahimachi.
そして19号通り。
And 19th Route.
19号があるらしいのじゃ。
There seems to be a 19th Route.
一旦進むか。
Let's advance a bit.
ちょっとなんか
Um, sort of...
こっちか。
This way?
こっちの方で19島松朝日、
This way, 19 Shimamatsu Asahi,
19号
19th Route...
なんかこっちの方な気はしていますのじゃ、島松、
Sort of feels like it's this way, Shimamatsu,
島松朝日。
Shimamatsu Asahi.
てか朝日ってさ、
Wait, Asahi,
朝日ってさ、
Asahi,
なんかこのへんに工場なかった？
Weren't there factories around here?
このへんに工場があったような気が、
Feels like there were factories around here,
島松、島松あるのじゃ！島松、
Shimamatsu, Shimamatsu exists! Shimamatsu,
島松朝日町。
Shimamatsu Asahimachi.
で、19号
And, 19th Route...
19号ってんなのじゃ？19号
What is the 19th Route? 19th Route...
19号ってんなのじゃ？
What is the 19th Route?
島松、
Shimamatsu,
島松
Shimamatsu...
道路？
Road?
道路なのじゃ？
Is it a road?
ちょっとでも0に寄せるには、もっと情報を得なきゃいけないから、
But to get closer to zero, I need to get more info,
さすがに動くか。
So I should probably move.
動かないものにはね、情報は与えられないのじゃ。
Things that don't move can't be given info.
どっち行く？
Which way to go?
どっち行くのがいいんだろうか。
Which way would be better?
川？
River?
小学校もある。
There's also an elementary school.
柏木川！
Kashiwagi River!
やった！みんな大好き島松小丸。
Yay! Everyone's favorite Shimamatsu Elementary.
これ来たんじゃない？川、川、川。
Didn't this come up? River, river, river.
柏木川を探していきますのじゃ。
Let's search for Kashiwagi River.
柏木川を探していきますのじゃ。柏木川あったのじゃ！
Let's search for Kashiwagi River. Kashiwagi River is here!
柏木川、
Kashiwagi River,
そして島松町、島松町を探していきますのじゃ。
and let's look for Shimamatsu-chō.
川の、えーっと、
The river's, um,
北かな？
North maybe?
川の北が、川が違うな。
North of the river, no, the river is different.
南北で流れてるのかな？
Is it flowing north and south?
南北で流れていって、
Flowing north and south,
こっち側に小学校が
On this side, the elementary school is...
島松町あってる。
Shimamatsu-chō, that's right.
島松町がこちらにございますのじゃ。
Shimamatsu-chō is right here.
島松町発見。で今いるのが
Shimamatsu-chō found. And right now I am...
ここかの？ここに来ていって、んで
Here? Coming here, and then...
戻るのじゃ。どっちから来たっけわし。
Going back. Which way did I come from?
わしどっちから来たっけ？
Which way did I come from?
ああなるほど。
Ah, I see.
こっちからきてるっぽいのか。
Looks like I came from this way.
レスポンスのじゃ。レスポンスして
Let's respond. Respond and...
ここかなあ。
probably here.
で、このへんに多分住宅地が
And around here, there should be...
あって、って感じな気がして折るのじゃ。
some residential area... I feel like.
のじゃ。うん。じゃあ
So, let's turn around. Hmm.
いや、こっから寄せるの苦手なのじゃ。ええと、
Man, I'm bad at gathering from here, jeez.
左より、左よりで、
left-ish, left-ish, and
左よりで、こっち川で、
left-ish, on this side,
うーんのじゃ。
man...
こっちかな?この、こっちとか。
Is it this way? Or this way?
んで、南に合わせて、
And, lining it up to the south...
いや、むずいのじゃ。よいしょ!
Man, this is tough! Yoish!
2メートルなのじゃ!
2 meters!
近づいてはいるけど、難しいのじゃ。
I got close, but it's hard!
これ完全に寄せ切るってめちゃくちゃ難しいのじゃ。
Gathering it completely is super hard, you know?
ね、うん。ゼロはうん。
Right? Luck. Zero is luck.
次いくのじゃ。次!
Next one, then. Next!
うーん、なんか高岡市、
Hmm, looks like Takaoka City...
高岡市多いのじゃ?高岡市、ええと高岡市のどこという話なんだが
Takaoka City has a lot, huh? Takaoka City.
どっちに道路あるかな?いったん南に進んでみるのじゃ。
Where are the roads? Let's try heading south first.
南に進んでみるのじゃ。
Let's try heading south.
南に進んでみますのじゃ。よいしょ。
Let's try heading south. Yoish!
うお、めっちゃ広い。
Whoa, super wide!
南じゃなかったかの?
Was that not south?
でもここ、川の匂いしない?
Wait, does that smell like a river?
西から川の匂いするのじゃ!西から川の匂いするから、さすがに高岡市のこっち側だと思うのじゃ。これ絶対川だよ。
I smell a river from the west! It smells like a river from the west, so surely...
川の匂いするのじゃ。
It smells like a river, you know.
川の匂い。
River smell...
まあ、もっと進んでみる。進んでみますのじゃ。よいしょ。
Well, let's keep going. Let's keep going. Yoish!
建物系がね、あるといいんだが。
It would be nice if there were buildings...
こっちはもう川じゃからあれかの。
This side is already a river, so maybe...
あんまりかの。うん、やっぱドカワ、ドカワがある。
Not really, huh? Yeah, there's a levee. A levee exists.
なるほどね。なんか北に進んだほうがいけるかのかの。
I see. Moving north might be better, maybe?
ちょっと北に戻ってみますのじゃ。よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ。
Let's try going back north a bit. Yoish, yoish, yoish.
黒くなっちゃった。
It went pitch black.
土手はあんま情報ないかのか。レスポンスして戻って、
There isn't much info on the levee, huh? Respond and go back,
こっち進んだから北に進んでみますのじゃ。よいしょ。
and since we came this way, let's try heading north. Yoish!
よいしょ。
Yoish!
北に進みましたのじゃ。
We headed north, you know.
なんかあるかのか。もうちょい進むのじゃ。よいしょ。よいしょ。
Is there something? Let's go a bit further. Yoish! Yoish!
こっから来た?え、どっから来たか忘れなくなっちゃったのじゃ。もう一回、もう一回チャレンジ。
Where did we come from? I forgot where we came from, so let's try again.
うーん、こっち!こっち!よいしょ。
Um, this way! This way! Yoish!
こっち!よいしょ。
This way. Yoish!
こっち。じゃあこのまま人間と出会うまで進んでいきますのじゃ。
This way. Let's keep going until we meet people.
ソーラーパネルがめちゃくちゃいっぱいあるのじゃ!
There are so many solar panels, you know!
ソーラーパネルってどこにあるんじゃろ。
Where on earth are all these solar panels?
大体、あれなんか建物の匂い。
It's like, a building smell.
特にタイトルなし。タイトルなしの建物。
Especially no title. A building with no title.
でもなんかスクールバスとか書いてある。
But it says school bus or something.
西広上。
Nishiirokami.
ええと、射水市の西広上。西広上を探すのじゃ。
Let's look for Nishiirokami in Imizu City. Nishiirokami.
西広上。
Nishiirokami.
でも多分この、ここの川じゃからさっき見えた川が、このへんだと思うのじゃ。さっき高岡市書いてあったから、なんか間のどっかなのかなと予想していますのじゃ。
Well, I'm guessing it's somewhere in between because earlier Takaoka was written.
西広上探したいけど、西広上が、広上から探す?
I want to find Nishiirokami, but how do I find it from Hirokami?
西広上がわかんないのじゃ。西、ひろうえ。
I don't get Nishiirokami. Nishiirokami...
に、し、ひろうえ。ない。
Nishiirokami. Nope.
いったんもう一回の子タイトル見る。
Let's look at the title one more time.
あ、西広上って書いてる!
Ah, it says Nishiirokami!
西広上って書いてるのじゃ!え、大門小学校あるよ、大門小学校。
Nishiirokami, it says! And Daimon Elementary School is nearby. Daimon Elementary School.
小学校が近くにあるんじゃの。大門小学校がある、あり。
Elementary school is nearby, you know. Daimon Elementary School is there, right?
このへんめっちゃ発電所あるからこの、あ、広上ある!あ、西広上ある!西広上、
There are lots of power plants around here, so... Oh, Hiroe is there!
西白井
Nishishiroi.
ん、西白井あるけど、
Hmm, there's Nishishiroi, but...
そもそも川の方角が、
First of all, the river's direction...
川が？
The river?
こっちだから、
It's on this side, so
こっちな気がするけど。
I feel like it's this way, but.
ん、だこ、この川か？
Hmm, thi- this river?
ここのかの可能性もある？
Could this be the river?
うん、ま、いったんこのへんで見ておいて
Yeah, well, I think I'll look around here for now
探してみようと思うのじゃ。
and try to search.
うん、でもやたらとさ、このさ発電所
Yeah, but for some reason, there are power plants
変電所みたいなのあるから、
and substations like this around,
なんかこっちでもおかしくないよね？
so wouldn't it be weird if it's over here too?
こっちでもおかしくないよねって思う。
I think it wouldn't be weird if it's over here either.
思い増すのじゃ。
That's what I think.
うん、ちょいいったんここブックマークしといて、
Yeah, let's bookmark this for a sec
戻るか。
and go back.
広上なのじゃ？
Is it Hirokami?
ちょっといったんレスポンス、レスポンスして、
Let's respond, respond for a bit
もう一回考え直すのじゃ。
and rethink it.
これじゃ嘘をたかおかしって書いてあるの。
It says "Uso Takaokashi" or something on this.
もう一回来た進むのじゃ、北進むじゃろ？
Let's go forward again, we go north, right?
北進むじゃろ？
Go north, right?
田んぼに出るじゃろ？
Come out to the rice fields, right?
来た、来た。
Came, came.
ん？さっきこ、この道だった？
Huh? Was this this road earlier?
さっきと違う道に来ちゃった？
Did I end up on a different road than before?
広上、広上でしたのじゃ。
It was Hirokami, Hirokami.
失礼いたしましたのじゃ。
Excuse me.
で、さっきと違う道に来ちゃった気がするのじゃ。
And I feel like I ended up on a different road than before.
どっから来た？よーし、橋見つけたい。
Where did I come from? Alright, I want to find a bridge.
あ、じゃあ橋を探しに行くのじゃ。
Ah, then I'll go look for a bridge.
多分西広上にいるということは北に行けば橋があるはずじゃから、
Since I'm probably in West Hirokami, if I go north there should be a bridge,
いったん北に向かって、てか土手このへんじゃろ。
so once heading north, wait, the embankment should be around here.
北に向かって、てか土手、川を、
Heading north, wait, the embankment, the river...
川を北上したくないですか？
don't you want to go north along the river?
なんか書いてある。
Something is written.
これ読めない？
Can't read this?
これ読めないのじゃ？
ちょっと読ませていただきたいです。
I'd like to read it for a bit.
うん、読めないのじゃ。
Yeah, can't read it.
さっき石水石って書いてあったのじゃ。
It said Sekisuiseki earlier.
で、わしどこから来たか分かんなくて、
And I don't know where I came from,
で、わしどこから来たじゃろな。
and where did I come from?
大門町、大門町来た！大門町。
Daimon-cho, Daimon-cho came! Daimon-cho.
大門町を探すのじゃ。
Search for Daimon-cho.
このへん大門書いてあるけどね。
Daimon is written around here though.
大門町というネーミングにはなっていない感じなのだじゃ。
It doesn't seem to have the naming Daimon-cho.
もう消えたネーミング？
A vanished naming?
消えたネーミングなのだじゃ。
It's a vanished naming.
合併とかあった？
Was there a merger or something?
大門町ないけど。
Daimon-cho isn't there though.
でも大門とは書いてるから、多分名残り、名残りはあおのじゃ。
But it says Daimon, so probably remnants, remnants are there.
大門町。
Daimon-cho.
あと、なんか神社っぽいもの。
And also, some shrine-like thing.
迷子のわしは誰が拾ってくれるんじゃろ。
Who will pick up a lost soul like me?
迷子になったらお主らが連れてってくれるの？わしのこと。
When I get lost, will you take me along? Me.
で、川なくなった！え、川さっきまであった川が、消えたのじゃ。
And the river disappeared! The river that was there until earlier disappeared.
あ、ある、あるのじゃ。
Ah, it's there, it's there.
西に川がある。え、西に川がある？
There's a river to the west. Eh, there's a river to the west?
妙なのじゃ。
That's strange.
妙じゃないのじゃ。
It's not strange.
え、じゃ、これなのだじゃ、きっと。
Eh, then this is probably it.
え、これじゃない？
Eh, isn't this it?
わしが見えてたさっきのやつ、これじゃない？
Isn't this what I saw earlier?
これ切れない？矢田車？
Can't this cut? Yatasha?
切れない？
Can't cut?
そんなことはないかも。
That might not be the case.
あ、これこっちの可能性もあるのだじゃ。
Ah, there's also the possibility of this side.
トイレ、トイレもある。
Toilet, there's a toilet too.
川に近づきたいのだじゃ。
I want to get closer to the river.
ちょ、川に近づかせていただきますのだじゃ。
Um, let me get closer to the river.
石水石って書いてあるのだじゃ。
It says Sekisuiseki.
これ石水石なの？
Is this Sekisuiseki?
川に近づかせていただくのだじゃ。
I'll have you let me get closer to the river.
これね、土手に、北方向の、え、でも北に、北にあるよ。
This, on the embankment, going north, eh, but it's north, it's in the north.
北にあるってことはこっち側な気がするけどな。北にあるってことはこっち側な気がするけど。
Being in the north makes me feel like it's this side though. Being in the north makes me feel like it's this side.
ダメなのだじゃ？
Is no good?
なんか、こっちな気がするけど。
Somehow, I feel like it's this way.
このへんな気がするけど。
I feel like it's around here.
で、さっき見えてたのこれな、ここじゃろ絶対に道！
And what I saw earlier, this, it must be the road right here!
こんな角度じゃったよ。
It was at an angle like this.
絶対このへんだろう。
It definitely must be around here.
って思うんじゃが。
That's what I think, though.
絶対ここじゃろ！ちょ、いったんここだとして。
It's definitely here! Hold on, supposing it's here.
一ったんここだとして。
Supposing it's here for a sec.
あもう、にゃあ、なのじゃ。
Ah jeez, meow.
一ったんここだとして。
Supposing it's here for a sec.
こうじゃったら。
If it's like this.
ここだとして、こうじゃったら。
Supposing it's here, if it's like this.
なんか、このへんの市街地のどっかなのじゃ。
Somehow, it's somewhere in the urban area around here.
このへんの市街地のどっかな気が…。
I feel like it's somewhere in the urban area around here...
する、さん、3差路の道。どこじゃろ？なんかこの辺とか。
Hmm, which way? Three intersections? Where could this be? Somewhere around here, maybe?
この辺な気がするのじゃ。進むのじゃ！
I feel like it's around here. Let's move forward!
よいしょ！
There we go!
よい、み、道ももう一回ちゃんと見とくか。
Let me check the roads properly just in case.
ここじゃね？うん。道の角度が一緒なのじゃ。
Is it right here? Yeah, the road angle matches.
ここなのじゃ。うん。ここなのじゃあ！
Is it right here? Yeah, it's right here!
え、た、たぶん。たぶんね。
Let's see. Probably... probably here.
たぶんここだから、この辺に置くのじゃ。
Since it's probably here, it's gonna be around this spot.
のじゃ！0メートルなのじゃあ！
It's right here! Zero meters, baby!
ゼロゲス。ゼロゲスなのだ。
Zero guess? Zero guess, baby!
やったのじゃあ！
Nailed it!
難しかったのじゃ。難しかったのじゃ。
That was tricky. That was tricky.
川に、川に惑わされるのじゃ。次行くのじゃ！
Getting tricked by the river. Next, let's go!
よいしょ。
Let's go!
なんか情報が多そう。きゅっとした家がいっぱいなのだ。
There's a lot of info. Lots of compact houses.
きゅっとしているから、
Since it's compact...
三井のリパーク。東京か？杉並。
Suginami, Tokyo?
杉並、宮前、ちょっとちゃんと読めないのじゃ。
Suginami, Miyamae... I can't read it properly.
えっと、杉並、宮前5丁目。宮前？宮前ってどこなのだじゃ？
Suginami, Miyamae 5-chome. Miyamae...
まあ、一旦、一旦これは宮前5丁目ってのを覚えておいて、
Well, for now, let's remember it's Miyamae 5-chome.
道とかを探したほうが早そうなのだ。東京だし。
It looks faster to search for roads. It's Tokyo, after all.
よいしょ。道に出ていきますのじゃ。南へ。
Here we go. Heading out to the street. Heading south.
南へ進む。南へ進むと、
Heading south...
のじゃ。くねくねしてる。ねくね、くねくねしてるのじゃ！
It's winding around. Winding, winding!
くねくねしてるのじゃ！
It's winding around!
川もあるよ。川もあるのじゃ。
There's a river. There's a river!
井なり、井なり立教。川があるから水探すのじゃ。
Inari-Rikyo. There's a river, so let's look for water.
水。でもこんな太くないよね。もっと細い川だと思うんじゃが。
Water. But it's not this thick, right? I'd think it's a thinner river.
井なり立教っていうの。すぎ、杉並広いから、の、でも杉並広いのじゃ。
Inari-Rikyo... Suginami is wide, so... but Suginami is wide, right?
杉並から井なり立教を探す。
From Suginami, let's find Inari-Rikyo.
くねくね。井なり立教を探さなきゃいけない。
Windy, windy. We need to find Inari-Rikyo.
川の名前を知りたいのじゃ、橋の名前じゃなくて。
I want to know the name of the river, not the bridge.
橋の名前を教えて。
Tell me the name of the bridge!
あ、でもここに住所書いてある。ちょ、これ見るのじゃ。
Oh, but there's an address written here. Let's look at this.
この住所を。あ、角度的に見えないのじゃ。
This address... Ah, the angle makes it hard to see.
よいしょ。見せて。「注意！！とびだし多し」
Hold on, let me see. "Caution: Children darting out."
とびだし注意。とびだし注意じゃなくて。ちょ、住所見れる場所探すのじゃ。
Not children darting out... Let's find a place where I can see the address.
杉並区、あった！久我山三丁目。久我山を探すのじゃ。
Found it! Kugayama 3-chome. Let's search for Kugayama!
久我山を探すのじゃ。風吹先輩いたのじゃ？
Let's search for Kugayama! Fuzuki-senpai was here, right?
うちは地図を見てて気づけなかったのじゃ。配信終わったら見えるのじゃ。
I was looking at the map and couldn't figure it out. I'll see it after the stream ends.
久我山ないのじゃ。探すのじゃ。
Kugayama isn't showing. Gotta search for it.
もっと広い道行きたい。
I want to go to a wider road.
え、鉄道？これ鉄道なの？本当だ！
Huh? A railway? Is this a railway? It's true!
鉄道なのじゃ。北に。北に鉄道。
It's a railway! North. There's a railway to the north.
気づかなかったのじゃ。
I didn't notice!
北に鉄道。久我山。情報量が多いのじゃ。久我山、久我山。
North of the railway is Kugayama... So much information! Kugayama, Kugayama.
探すのじゃ、探すのじゃ！
Let's search, search!
もっと広い道出たい。広い道に出ます。
I want to get to a wider road. Let's head to a wider road.
東京は苦手なのだ。東京のマップは。
I'm bad with Tokyo. Tokyo maps aren't my specialty.
あんまり得意じゃないのじゃ。よいしょ。よいしょ。よいしょ。よいしょ。でっかい建造物。
Let's go!
物見つけたいのじゃ。
I want to find something.
でっかい建造物。
A huge building.
迷子、迷子、迷子。
Lost, lost, lost.
こっち進めなくない？
Can't we go this way?
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
ねぇ、鉄道ヒントなのじゃ？北に鉄道があったのじゃ。
Hey, is the railway a hint? There was a railway to the north.
あ！
Ah!
ちょっと安心する！安心するのじゃ！
I'm a bit relieved! I'm relieved!
ちょっと広めの道に来た！
I've come to a somewhat wider road!
久我山稲荷！
Kugayama Inari!
久我山らしい、やっぱ。
It's Kugayama-like, after all.
やっぱ久我山、
It's Kugayama, after all,
久我山駅というのがある。
there's something called Kugayama Station.
駅から探すのがよさそうなのじゃ。
It might be good to search from the station.
久我山駅というものが ありますのじゃ。
Something called Kugayama Station exists.
久我山駅探すか。
Shall I look for Kugayama Station?
じゃ、さっきのは……あ、あった、久我山駅めっちゃあるやん！めっちょありましたのじゃ。
Well, the last one... Ah, there are so many Kugayama Stations! There were a lot.
久我山稲荷神社もありましたのじゃ。失礼いたしましたのじゃ。
Kugayama Inari Shrine was also there. Excuse me.
え、じゃ川とかもさ、川とかも見つけられそうじゃない？
Eh, then wouldn't it be possible to find rivers and things too?
なんて川にいたかをもう、もうけっこう忘れちゃったんじゃが、めっちゃ動いてるのじゃ。
I've pretty much forgotten what river I was at, but I'm moving a lot.
あ、違う！違う違う違う！
Ah, no! No, no, no!
駐車場にヒントめっちゃ書いてあった気がするのじゃ。よいしょ、よいしょ。
I feel like there were a lot of hints written in the parking lot. Heave-ho, heave-ho.
浜田山宮前へ……え、5丁目。
To Hamadayama Miyamae... Eh, 5-chome.
ここから浜田山5丁目を探す作戦、駐車場を探す作戦なのだ。
The strategy to search for Hamadayama 5-chome from here, searching for a parking lot.
うん、ここから駐車場を探させていただきますのじゃが、
Yeah, I'll have you let me search for a parking lot from here, but
じゃが、もしくはこのへんの建物のタイトル、建物のタイトルを知りたいのじゃ。
or I want to know the title of the buildings around here.
え、でも建物のタイトルになりうる建物がない、一軒家ばかり。
Eh, but there are no buildings that could have titles, mostly detached houses.
タイトルがあるのは集合住宅だから
The ones with titles are apartment complexes, so
浜田山第3駐車場。
Hamadayama Dai-3 Parking Lot.
タイトルないのじゃ。
There's no title.
うーん、うーん、うーん、うーん、探したい。
Hmm, hmm, hmm, hmm, I want to find it.
読み込んでほしいのじゃあ。
I want you to load it.
ふむふむふむ、浜田山5の8。
Hmm hmm hmm, Hamadayama 5-8.
やっぱ浜田山なのだ、久我山じゃなくて浜田山にいるのじゃ。
It's Hamadayama after all, I'm in Hamadayama, not Kugayama.
浜田山を探すのじゃ、さすがにこのへんのどっかにいる気がする。
I'll search for Hamadayama, as expected I feel like I'm somewhere around here.
そうビルとかアパート名、タイトルなのだ。
Right, building or apartment names, titles.
浜田山、浜田山、ない、ないのじゃ？久我山まではいけた。
Hamadayama, Hamadayama, none, none? I got as far as Kugayama.
都会苦手なのだ、情報が多すぎてどこを見ればいいか分かんなくて、
I'm bad with cities, there's too much information and I don't know where to look,
わかんなくて、浜田山浜田山、浜田山浜田山、西浜田、西浜田！
I don't know, Hamadayama Hamadayama, Hamadayama Hamadayama, Nishihamada, Nishihamada!
西浜田ってことは、もうちょい東に……浜田山！
Nishihamada means a bit more east... Hamadayama!
浜田山あったのじゃあ！
Hamadayama was there!
たどり着くのがずいぶんとう時間を要してしまったようなのじゃ。
It seems it took quite a bit of time to arrive.
もっかい見るのじゃ。
I'll look again.
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、浜田山5丁目。
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho, Hamadayama 5-chome.
5丁目……えっと、1、2、5丁目どこなのだ？4、
5-chome... um, 1, 2, where is 5-chome? 4,
5丁目ない？駐車場多くない？駐車場めっちゃ多いのじゃ。
No 5-chome? Aren't there many parking lots? There are a lot of parking lots.
浜田山4、浜田山4丁目なのだ。
Hamadayama 4, it's Hamadayama 4-chome.
駐車場が多いですのじゃ。
There are many parking lots.
5丁目今探してます。5丁目あったのじゃ！
I'm looking for 5-chome now. 5-chome was there!
これが浜田山5丁目の予感、5丁目の予感なんじゃが、じゃがではあって、
This is a hunch for Hamadayama 5-chome, a hunch for 5-chome, but, it is, though,
浜田山4丁目、5丁目、第5！
Hamadayama 4-chome, 5-chome, Dai-5!
第5じゃって！第5じゃって！
Dai-5! Dai-5!
いっぱいありすぎてどれが第5かわかんないのじゃ。
There are too many, I don't know which one is Dai-5.
ちょ、さっき住所見つけたからもうっかいそこ行こう。
Hold on, I found the address earlier so let's go back there.
北に行って、よいしょ。
Go north, heave-ho.
浜田山5の8、5の8、これ、5の8。
Hamadayama 5-8, 5-8, this, 5-8.
5の8。
5-8.
5の8
他のここなんのじゃ? 5の8
What's this other place? 5-8.
この辺の駐車場能動っか
Some parking lot around here...
駐車場ってタイト...あ、宮前5って書いてる！
Parking lot... Ah, it says Miyamae 5!
これじゃない?
Isn't this it?
もししてこれ?
Could it be this?
違うのかな?
Is it different?
回戻るのじゃ。何度でも。
Let's go back again. As many times as it takes.
宮前5丁目第5
Miyamae 5-chome, No. 5.
こっから第5じゃろ?
It's No. 5 from here, right?
でも、地図的におかしくて
But geographically it's weird...
ここにあるイースト...
The East... around here...
東にあるから
...is to the east,
東にあるからこの辺な気がする。
so I feel like it's around here.
ちょ、道見る。道見るのじゃ。
Hold on, check the road. Let's check the road.
来た。
Here.
ん? 道的に違う。
Hm? Road-wise, it's different.
道的に違うのじゃ。
Road-wise, it's different.
なんか、東にある
Something... is to the east...
三井のリパーク書いてるかの？
Does it say Mitsui's Repark?
三井のリパーク、カーシェアだと書いてあるのかの?
Does it say Mitsui's Repark Car Share?
パーキングは書いてない感じがするの。
Doesn't feel like 'parking' is written.
信号ね、信号探したいのじゃ。
Traffic lights... I want to find a traffic light.
北に行くと信号があるのかな?
If I go north, is there a traffic light?
5の8
5-8.
北に行って5の8があるということは
If 5-8 is further north,
北に行って5の8があるということは、この辺? 北に行って5の8
then around here? Going north, 5-8.
ふんふんふん。
Hmm, hmm, hmm.
ガチムズなのだじゃ。
This is super hard.
パーキングも大体書いてある。
Parking is mostly written too.
えじゃ、わしが見たパーキング違うのかも。
Well, maybe the parking I saw was different.
この辺だと思うんじゃが、北進んでみるのじゃ。
I think it's around here, let's try heading north.
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho.
信号、信号あり。
Traffic light, traffic light ahead.
あれ? わかんない道きちゃった。もう回。
Huh? I came to a road I don't know. Let's go again.
もう回いきますのじゃ。
Let's go again.
この会計事務所とかで、あ、会計事務所ある。
At this accounting office or something... Ah, there's an accounting office.
えじゃ、合ってるのじゃ?
Well, is that right?
じゃあ合ってたのじゃ、ここなのだじゃ。
Then it was right, it's right here.
ここでしたのじゃ。
It was right here.
ということは、ここなのだじゃ。
That means it's right here.
ようやく、ようやくここなのだじゃー！
Finally, finally it's right here!
東京っててごたえですのじゃー！
Tokyo is so tough!
てごたかったのじゃ。
It was tough.
情報量に弱いなじゃ。
I'm weak against too much info.
最後行くのじゃー！
Going for the last one!
あ、安心する。
Ah, what a relief.
開けた道、でもちょっと
An open road, but a bit...
にしてももっとほしいのじゃー！
Even so, I want more!
ちょっと開けすぎている。
It's a bit too open.
でも山が、結構山脈、雪印がっかってる山脈があるから
But there are mountains, quite a few mountain ranges with snow caps, so
結構山で大体の位置が山さえわかれば
if we know roughly where the mountains are, if we know the mountains,
地方さえわかれば行けそうな変わりはしていいますのじゃ。
if we know the region, we can probably go there.
のでおった電柱を探したいのじゃ。
So I want to find the utility poles.
よいしょ、よいしょ。のじゃあ！
Heave-ho, heave-ho! No ja!
違う、これ景色なのか。
Wait, is this the scenery?
よいしょ、よいしょ。すすめ、すすめ、すすめ、すすめ、すすめ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho. Move forward, move forward...
中山ライオンズクラブ
Nakayama Lions Club
これなんかそれで特定できる人いそうなのじゃ。
Looks like someone could identify the place from this.
そういうので特定できる人いそうな情報、中山町
Information that might help identify it: Nakayama-machi.
わしはちょっとわからないから進むのじゃ。
I don't quite get it, so I'll keep going.
まだまだ進むのじゃ。
Still going further.
なんか進んでいくとこっちじゃないような感じ
As I go further, it feels like it's not this way...
こっちじゃないような感じ。
...feels like it's not this way.
なんか書いてありそう。
Looks like something is written.
見して、見して。山形だ！
Let me see, let me see. It's Yamagata!
山形何川? 滝川? 滝川?
Yamagata, which river? Takigawa?
なんかそういうのあった気がするのじゃ。
I feel like there was something like that.
そういう市ががあったようななかったような気がしているのじゃ。
I feel like there was or wasn't a city like that.
一旦山形が分かったから山形で山が
Now that I know it's Yamagata, in Yamagata the mountains...
どこだったっけ。ちょっと一旦これチェックポイントにして。
Where was it again? Let's make this a checkpoint for a moment.
山がどっちの方向にあったんだっけ？
Which direction were the mountains in again?
どっちにでかい山が？こっちか？
Where's the big mountain? This way?
えっと…
Let's see...
西？
West?
山形のこっち側なのじゃ？
Could it be this side of Yamagata?
山形のこっち側
This side of Yamagata...
中山町を発見！
I found Nakayama Town!
これなのじゃ。
This is it.
最上川…
The Mogami River...
さっきはこれは何にしに来たのじゃ？これ土手？
What did we come here for earlier? Is this a levee?
これ何？
What's this?
川管理用の通路
River management pathway.
何川管理用？
What river management?
すかわ、ここの川か？
Sugawa? Is this the river here?
ここか？ちょっと文字が
Here? The text is...
文字がつぶれてて
The text is blurred...
あ、これで読める。河川。
Oh, I can read it with this. River.
別にさっきの固有名称ではない。
It's not a specific proper noun.
固有名称じゃなかったのじゃ。
It wasn't a proper noun.
固有名称ではなかったけど
It wasn't a proper noun, but...
山はじゃあどっちかの山じゃない。川。
Then the mountains aren't on either side? The river.
で、川見つけないとさ。
And we need to find the river.
でも川、こっちかの
But the river on this side...
こっからが結構
From here it's quite...
長い？
long?
いや、嘘なのじゃ。
No, that's a lie.
なんか駐車場っぽいのが有るから、なんか施設である可能性があるのじゃ。
There seems to be a parking lot-like place, so it might be a facility.
クラブハウス、プレーの際にはクラブハウス等で利用受付
Club house, please register for use at the club house etc. when playing.
これが行くのが施設のなのだろう。
This is some kind of facility.
なんの施設かを当てさえすれば
If we can just figure out what kind of facility it is,
いけるかも？
we might be able to get there?
いけるかもしれないので
Since we might be able to get there,
施設を当てていくのじゃ。
let's guess the facility.
でなんかゴルフみたいなの持ってる。これ何してるのじゃ？何持ってるんだろう？杖？
And they're holding something like golf clubs. What are they doing? What are they holding? A cane?
これはただの杖？
Is this just a cane?
なんかゴルフな予感がしている
It feels like golf.
していって
Going along,
ゴルフ場とかなのかね？
is it a golf course or something?
ね、なんか、そんな感じするけどね。
Yeah, it kind of feels like that.
犬の糞は持ち帰りましょう
Please take your dog's waste home.
なんか旗とか立ってるし
And there are flags and stuff standing.
北側に
to the north side
ゴルフ、ゴルフ場こういうね
golf course, something like this.
こういうね、ひまわりグランド、こういうね
sunflower ground...
絶対ここじゃろ。公衆トイレとかあるよ。
It's definitely here, there are public toilets and everything.
これ、これ、これも道路もあるよ。
And there's also a road.
ゲートボール？
Gateball?
違うか。じゃあ違うかも。
Or not? Maybe not.
でめ公衆トイレ2個あるよ。そっちにもなかった？
But there are two public toilets. Weren't there any on the other side?
え、違う可能性があるのじゃ。
Ah, there's a possibility it's different.
そっちにはなかった気がするのじゃ。
I feel like there weren't any on that side.
なのじゃ。
That's right.
でもタイトル書いてないね。
But there's no title written.
タイトル書いてないね。それが気になるのじゃ。
There's no title. That's what bothers me.
え、でもトイレ2個あるよ？
Wait, but there are two toilets?
トイレ2個あるってこと、トイレげす
Having two toilets means... toilet guess...
トイレげすしたら起こるお主ら。
If I do a toilet guess, you guys will get mad.
でもなんかこの辺な気がするんじゃが、どうじゃ。
But I feel like it's around here, what do you think?
トイレげすしたら起こる。
If I do a toilet guess, you'll get mad.
うん、ちょにしぽんして
Yeah, let's pin west and...
え、でもこんな感じな気がするんじゃがのう。
But I feel like it's something like this.
するんじゃがの、この辺じゃろう。
It should be around here.
ねえ、だからこの道ね、これね
Hey, so this road, you know, this...
トイレでわかる。
I know from the toilets.
これ違ったらガチクヤシいなじゃ。
If this is wrong, it's really frustrating.
いくのじゃ。
Let's go.
よいしょー！
Heave-ho!
のじゃー！
Yay!
やったのじゃー！
We did it!
いや、なかなか時間がかかったの。35分もかかっちゃったのじゃ。
Man, it took quite a while. It took 35 minutes.
全部見つけるのに。何が一番時間かかったかの。
To find everything. Which one took the longest, I wonder?
4番、4番どれ？
Number 4, which is number 4?
東京、東京に一番時間かかってるよ！
Tokyo, Tokyo took the longest!
見て、お主ら、この左側でさ、
Look, you guys, on this left side,
それぞれさ、どれに何分かかったみたいなのさ、見れるんじゃが
you can see how many minutes each one took,
一番情報量が多いはずの東京に一番時間がかかっているのじゃ！
Tokyo, which should have the most information, took the longest!
難しいのじゃ。
It's difficult.
やっぱね、あのね、東京はね、情報量がね、なかなか多いのじゃ。
You know, Tokyo has quite a lot of information.
難しいのじゃ。
It's difficult.
やったのじゃー！
We did it!
今日は、今日のジオゲッサーはこの辺でおしまいにしようかなと思うので、
I think I'll wrap up today's GeoGuessr around here, so
お部屋戻すのじゃ。お部屋…
let's return to the room. The room...
戻るのじゃ
Time to go back.
よいしょ
There we go.
のじゃ～
Noja~
楽しみだったー
That was fun!
久しぶりにジオゲッサーやったのじゃ、めっちゃ楽しいのじゃ
Playing GeoGuessr for the first time in a while was super fun!
ジオゲッサー楽しいからいっぱいやりたい
GeoGuessr is so fun, I wanna play it a lot.
いっぱいやりたいのじゃ
I wanna play it a lot, noja!
今日は本当はリズム天国の予定だったんじゃが
Today was actually supposed to be Rhythm Heaven,
キャプチャーボード、キャプチャーボードがなかなか不調で機材トラブルでできなかったから
but my capture board was acting up and I had equipment trouble, so I couldn't.
またいずれ、またいずれやらせていただきたいのじゃ
So I'd love to do it again sometime in the future!
頑張ったのじゃー
I did my best~!
お主らジオゲッサーする？普段
Do you guys play GeoGuessr usually?
普段する？1人ではしない？
Normally? Not by yourselves?
もし全然1人でもするのじゃ？
Or do you play by yourselves?
楽しいのじゃ
It's fun.
なんか、頭を空っぽにしたい時に、景色を見てジオゲッサーするのじゃ
Like, when I want to clear my head, I look at the scenery and play GeoGuessr.
景色を見てジオゲッサーするのじゃ。やんない？
Looking at the scenery and playing GeoGuessr. You don't?
おすすめなのじゃ。パソコン持ってない？
I recommend it. Don't have a PC?
ジオゲッサースマホでもできるよ。
You can play GeoGuessr on smartphones too.
スマホでもね、アプリがあっての、できるのじゃ。見るのは好き。
There's an app for smartphones, so you can play. I like watching it though.
世界大会とかするこそめっちゃ気持ちいいよね。
Watching world championships and stuff feels amazing, right?
できないけどさ、なんかシュポポポポポポポポってさ、当てるのすごくない？
I can't do it, but isn't it amazing how they instantly guess where it is?
今日ねめらちゃんのグッズ買ってきたのじゃ。ぱあ！グッズ！
Today I bought Mela-chan's merch! Tada! Merch!
今までの配信で何度も何度も宣伝をしようとしてできなかったグッズ
Merch that I tried to promote over and over in past streams but couldn't.
ゲットしてくれた主（ぬし）いるのじゃ？いるのじゃ？
Are there any masters who managed to get it? Are there?
公式サイトの方で、なんか缶バッジとアクリルスタがもう全部手に入れてくださったみたいな
On the official site, it sounds like everyone got all the can badges and acrylic stands.
話を、聞いたのじゃ。聞きましたのじゃ。
I heard that story. I heard about it.
光栄ですのじゃ。グッズ買ったよ！
I am honored. You bought the merch!
なんか店舗の方でも店舗の方でもいっぱい手に入れてくださってるとの噂
Word is you guys bought a ton at the physical stores too.
あ、アクリル？アクリルと缶バッジは、えっと常設じゃない？あれって。
Ah, acrylic? Acrylic and can badges, aren't those permanent items? Those ones.
レギュラーアウトフィットって、なんかまた入荷の可能性あるんじゃ……
Regular outfits... there's a chance they might restock...
ちょっとごめん、あの違ったらごめん。だから嘘と思って聞いてほしいんじゃが、嘘と思って聞いてほしいんじゃが
Wait, sorry, sorry if I'm wrong. So please take this with a grain of salt, please take it as a lie, but...
なんか、あの、今しか買えないのって、あれだけ？
Like, is that the only thing you can't buy anytime anymore?
遊びまわりたいから出てるやつだけ？
Just the ones out for wanting to hang out?
ちょっとちゃんと把握してないのに喋るの良くないなこういうの。ちょっと調べよ。
It's bad of me to talk without fully grasping things like this. Let me check.
調べたいのじゃ。どうやって調べられる？
I wanna check. How can I look it up?
なんか遊びまわりたいの、Xとか見るか。
Like, wanting to hang out, let's look at X or something.
X出てた。負けた気持ちになる。
X came up. Makes me feel like a loser.
負けた気持ちになる！負けた気持ちになる！
Makes me feel like a loser! Makes me feel like a loser!
最近入荷あるの？カノン。
Is there a restock recently? Canon.
グッズ情報を探すのじゃ。よいしょよいしょ。
Searching for merch info. Heave-ho, heave-ho.
えーと、スターティングボイス。
Uhm, starting voice.
スターティングボイスはずっとあるのじゃ。
The starting voice is always available.
スターティングボイスずっとあるのじゃ。この先どのタイミングで
The starting voice is always available. At what timing in the future
どのタイミングでわしのこと好きになっても手に入れられるのがスターティングボイス。
can you fall in love with me and still get the starting voice?
あ、じゃあやっぱレギュラーアウトフィット、あの、アクリルとか缶バッジは、おそらく、おそらく追加販売があるのではと予想しているのじゃ。
Ah, so I guess regular outfits, acrylics and can badges, are probably gonna have a second wave of sales, I'm guessing.
断言はしないのじゃ、怖いから。
I won't say for sure, 'cause I'm scared.
で、遊びまわりたいデビュー記念グッズは、これなんか詳細あったっけ？
And for the 'wanting to hang out' debut anniversary merch, did it have details?
詳細あった？いつまで売ってますみたいな。
Were there details? Like 'on sale until when'.
あったっけ？なんか、言われていたかも。
Was there? I might have been told about it.
なんかさ、デビュー記念グッズが5年後も売ってるとは思えないんじゃが、どうなんじゃ？
Like, I can't imagine debut anniversary merch still being sold 5 years later, what's that about?
さすがに5年後にはデビュー記念グッズじゃないグッズじゃろ？
Surely 5 years later it'd be non-debut anniversary merch, right?
どうなんだろ。
What could it be?
公式の情報を探しても分かんなかったんだよね。
Even after searching official info, I still didn't know.
不明なのじゃ。
So it's unknown.
ちょっと不明とさせていただくのじゃ。調べた上で不明とさせていただくのじゃ。
Let me treat it as unknown after doing some research.
そういうこともあるのじゃ。
That happens too.
うん。
Yeah.
ので、気になったお主らは
So, you guys are curious,
調べてくれると嬉しいのじゃ。
I'd be happy if you could look into it.
そしてあのグッズゲットしたよ情報も、えごサーチして見てますのじゃ。
And I also check out info on getting merch.
ハッシュタグあちちめらで見てますのじゃ。
I check with the hashtag #Hichimera.
なんかすでに、いたバッグとかをを作ったよみたいな、お写真とかも見て、はっかんなのじゃあって思ったのじゃ。
Seeing posts like "Already made a itabag and face," I thought, "That's amazing!"
すごくあったのじゃ！
It was so cool!
アクリルとかもね、お出かけに連れてってくれたり、
Also, things like taking the acrylic stand out when going places,
それこそあの、ネボックスのライブでなんか、メラ、ネボックスだよみたいな。
or even like "Metbox live and Mela is Neppox!" (laughs)
みたいなのも、見たのじゃ。見た！
I saw stuff like that too.
いろんなところにお出かけ、わしのことを連れてってくださってるのを、見舞いしたのじゃ。
Seeing everyone taking Washi and merch out to various places is wonderful.
ね、グッズ用のハッシュタグって作った方がいいの？どう思う？あった方がいい？
So, should we make a hashtag for goods? What do you think?
あった方がいいなら今作る？今作る？
If we should have one, I'll make it right now.
どうなのじゃ？
What do you think?
欲しい、わしら。
I want cute Washi.
分けた方が分かりやすいかも。
Should we separate them to make it easier to understand?
ネボックスで遊びに行ったのライブTシャツ、それはネボックスのTシャツ着てほしいのじゃ。
If Neppox has a T-shirt for their live, I want you to wear Neppox's T-shirt.
(笑)
(laughs)
それはネボックスのなんか来てほしいのじゃ。
I want you to come in Neppox stuff.
え、グッズとボイスタグ一緒にしていイイ？
Should goods and voice tags be together?
一緒ににしてほし。
I want you to be together.
一緒の方が楽じゃの。一緒にしたいのじゃ。
Being together is easier, right? I want us to be together.
何がいいかな、グッズと
What would be good, goods and...
あ、そ、見てみてけ、見てみてけ。
"Look and see"? "Look and see"?
見てみてにする？
Make it "Look and see"?
みて、みてのじゃとか、みてのな、どういうのがいいのじゃ？
"Look, look" and "Look, look" no ja?
お別れの挨拶決まってるのじゃ。
The greeting is decided, right?
えっとね、初めの挨拶が「のじゃあー」でね、
The first greeting is "No jaaaaー"!
終わりの挨拶が、えっと、
And the ending greeting is...
「さらばじゃあー」なのじゃ。
"Saraba jaaaaー"!
別がいい？一緒にした方がわし見やすいから一緒でいい？
Separate is fine too. Washi's side is easier to see if we're together, so is together okay?
一緒の方がみやすい。メラちゃんみてみて。
Together is easier to see. Mela-chan, look at me.
あちちみて、あちちみての、あ、あちちみていいの？あちちみていいじゃん。
Achichi, look. Is "Achichi, look" good?
あちちみてひらがなななのじゃ。
"Achichi, look" in Hiragana?
あちちみて！かわいいのじゃ。
"Achichi, look"! Cute, no ja.
あちちみてで、わしが
"Achichi, look" and Washi will...
グッズとかボイスの感想とか
see goods or voice review and stuff.
見たいのじゃ。
I want to see them.
あとでTwitterでもこれを報告しようと思うのじゃ。
I'm thinking of reporting this on Twitter later too.
うん、全部ひらがながかわいいのじゃ。
All in Hiragana is cute, no ja.
ボイスの感想とかグッズとか、こういうふうに飾ってるよとか、そういうのはあちちみてで投稿してほしいのじゃ。
If you post with "Achichi, look" when showing off voice reviews, goods, etc.,
かわいいタグを考えた。
Cute tag, I thought of it.
わしが考えたんじゃないけど(笑)かわいいタグを考えたのじゃ。
Washi thought of it, right? (laughs) I thought of a cute tag, no ja.
うん、全部ひらがなで、あちちみてなのじゃ。
Everything in Hiragana, with "Achichi, look", no ja.
いい感じなのじゃ。
It has a good vibe, no ja.
やったのじゃ。
Done, no ja.
今日伝えきれてないことある？今日伝えきれてないことあるかな？のじゃ。
Is there anything I haven't told you today?
えっと、あ、あしたの枠立てしてないのじゃ！
Ah, I haven't set up tomorrow's schedule, no ja!
配信終わったらさあ、明日空気読みの配信をしようと思うから、その枠を立てるのじゃ。
After the stream ends, I'll set up the frame for tomorrow's Reading the Atmosphere stream.
ハートタグはもうあるのじゃ。メラグミエズ。
Heart tag is already there, no ja. Melagumiez.
Twitterのプロフィールに乗ってるのじゃ。
It's listed on my Twitter profile, no ja.
ハートタグとあと何じゃ？
Heart tag and...
何があったかな。ハートタグと、もう一個タグあったのじゃ。
What else was there? Heart tag and...
何だっけ？配信中タグ？
What was it? "Streaming tag"?
あ、メラグミ出動中が配信の
Ah, "Melagumi Shutodochu" is for the stream.
やつ キャプチャーはえっと明日までに治らなくても
Well, the capture board...
そのSwitchを写すキャプチャーボードが不調なだけじゃから
just lets you stream Switch gameplay,
SwitchじゃなくてそのSwitchじゃないゲームPCゲーとかは
so games that aren't on Switch, like PC games,
写るのじゃ。PCゲーは写りますのじゃ。
will show up just fine.
メンバーシップがいつになるかはわからないのじゃ。
As for members-only streams, I'm not sure yet.
いっぱいの方が見てくださったらおそらくその収益化の条件みたいなのが満たせる気がしますのじゃ。
If lots of people come watch, I feel like we might meet the monetization requirements...
うん。
Yeah.
明日月曜日？え、あっという間なのじゃ。
Tomorrow is Monday?! That was so fast!
あっという間に月曜日になるの。ねえ、まだカクカクするのはどうすればいいのじゃおのれ直したはずなのだが。
How did Monday come so fast? I thought I fixed it!
直したはずなのだがちょっとこれもいずれ解決
I thought I fixed it,
したのじゃ！なんでなのじゃ！
but why?! Why is it happening again?
え、結構ちゃんとしたパソコンを用意したはずなのだが
I thought I prepared a pretty decent computer, too.
結構ちゃんとしたのを用意したはずなのだがなぜだか
I prepared a pretty decent one, so why?
うん設定もう回見直そうと思いますのじゃ。
I think I need to check my settings again.
ちょっとずつこういうトラブルが減っていけるように減っていけるようにするのじゃ。
So that these kinds of troubles happen less and less.
明日平日なのだ。おむしろ平日いや
Tomorrow is a weekday, right? I'd rather have weekdays off.
GPUでエンコードする設定に今日変えたはずなのだがなぜこんなことに。
I changed my settings to encode with GPU today, so why on earth...
なぜこんなことに。
Why did this happen?
明日は月曜日なのじゃと言ってくださいなのだ。明日月曜日なのじゃあ！
Please just say tomorrow is Monday! Tomorrow is Monday!
月曜日なのだ。平日は
It's Monday. Weekdays are...
おむしろ平日はお仕事とか学校とかあるからあれかノーやっぱ配信見るの難しい？
Well, people have work and school on weekdays, so it might be harder to watch streams.
リアルタイムとかだとやっぱお仕事中とかだったりするかも。今もお仕事中で今、今のこのワシの発言はアーカイブで聞いてる人もいるかもしれないのじゃ。
With real-time streams, people might be busy with work, but some might be listening to my rants in the archive right now.
ありがとなのじゃ。
Thank you!
夜なら大丈夫？
Nighttime is okay, right?
なんでそんなこと言うの、言えって言われましたのじゃ誘導誘導なのだ。誘導されたのじゃ。
Why would you say that? You're saying that because you were told to! You were guided/led into saying that!
今、今わし、わしは今、でも誘導されたと入札するのは配信者としてはあれかノー
Now, now... as a streamer, taking responsibility for everything you say...
やはり全ての発言に責任を持つべきだからやはり事実陳列罪というものがあって気をつけるのじゃ。
Well, you need to be careful because there's such a thing as "fact-checking" your statements.
気をつけますのじゃ。火の用心じゃ。怖いのだ。
I'll be careful. Fire is scary.
誘導されても、誘導されたら何の言い訳もないのじゃ！ちゃんと自分で思考して、ちゃんと自分で選択して、した上で発言しますのじゃああ！
Just because you were led into saying something doesn't mean it's an excuse! You have to think and choose for yourself before you speak!
気をつけるのじゃ。
I'll be careful.
気をつけますのじゃ。
知ってますのじゃ。
I know.
だから明日からは19時、19時に
So starting tomorrow, streams will usually be at 19:00.
えっと配信が大体あって水曜日は朝の7時、
And on Wednesdays, there'll be a stream at 7:00 in the morning,
朝の7時に配信がありますので通学中とか出勤中とか準備中とかに見てほしいのじゃ。
so please tune in while commuting or getting ready for work!
応援してほしい！頑張れおのら。
I'm cheering for you! Do your best, everyone!
生活人間としての社会に適応するための生活応援してるのじゃ！頑張れなのじゃ。
I'm supporting you in living your daily lives to fit into society as human beings. Do your best!
うちはパソコン頑張って直すのじゃ。ふふふふ。うちは頑張ってパソコン直すのじゃ。応援してますのじゃ。
As for me, I'll do my best to fix my PC. I'm rooting for you all!
うん。
Yeah.
アーカイブでも見る？嬉しいのじゃ。アーカイブでまで見てくれるの嬉しいのじゃ。コメントとかもねアーカイブ勢の人とかもねしてくれてるの見てるんじゃが、すごく嬉しい。
I'm so happy when people watch the archives, too. Seeing people comment in the archives makes me so happy.
嬉しいのじゃ。
I'm so happy.
なんか元気出したいってなったら歌ってみた動画とか聞くと元気出るかもしれない。
Whenever I want to cheer up, listening to singing videos always gives me energy.
なのじゃ
That's right.
よし、話したいこと話せた気がするのじゃ。
All right, I feel like I talked about everything I wanted to.
話せたのじゃ。
I really said it all.
だから今日は、おしまい！
So today's stream is over!
今日の配信はおしまいなのだ。
Today's broadcast is finished.
もう一回最後の挨拶を教える。
I'll teach you the final greeting once more.
お面外してほしい？
You want me to take off the mask?
すぐ外すのじゃ！
I'll take it off right away!
うん。
Yep.
最後の挨拶するのじゃー！
Time for our final greeting!
最後の挨拶は「さらばじゃー」で、
For our final greeting, say "Farewell,"
お願いしますのじゃ。
if you please.
お主ら準備はいい？
Are you guys ready?
行くのじゃー！
Here we go!
それじゃあ、また明日の配信で会うのじゃ。
Well then, I'll see you in tomorrow's stream.
さらばじゃー！
Farewell!
ご視聴感謝なのじゃ！
Thanks for watching!